<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes</title>
    <description>My notes in a clean jekyll format.</description>
    <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://Blackoctopus.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Memorial Gardens</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?nid=648&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to Jacksonville, NC - Official Website&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;jacksonville-nc---official-website&quot;&gt;Jacksonville, NC - Official Website&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens in Jacksonville is home to the Beirut Memorial, Onslow Vietnam Veteran’s Memorial and the 9/11 Memorial. Acreage within the gardens is reserved for future memorials, an amphitheater and the Museum of the Marine. Lejeune Memorial Gardens is located on Montford Point Road near the Freedom Fountain, downtown Jacksonville and the entrance to Camp Geiger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free parking is available on Montford Point Road at the entrance to Lejeune Memorial Gardens. Informational Placards are located at the site. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?nid=224&quot;&gt;Jacksonville Transit&lt;/a&gt; has a stop located within walking distance to Lejeune Memorial Gardens.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jacksonvilleonline.org&quot;&gt;Jacksonville-Onslow Chamber of Commerce&lt;/a&gt; website includes a listing of places to stay in Jacksonville during your visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing Memorials at Lejeune Memorial Gardens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/2014-10-Beirut_Mem_Observance-IMG_1961.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beirut Memorial, Jacksonville NC&quot; /&gt;Beirut Memorial
The Beirut Memorial was a gift from the citizens of Onslow County to honor the men that lived among us and gave so much. A solemn tribute to 273 Marines who gave their lives in Lebanon and Grenada on October 23, 1983. The names of each man are engraved in granite along with the words “They Came In Peace.” An annual Observance remembers those who lost theirs lives during the Beirut Peace Mission in 1983. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=585&quot;&gt;visit web page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/2014-VVMemorial9w.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Onslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial&quot; /&gt;O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial
The Onslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial is dedicated to all men and women who served during the Vietnam War, and stands as recognition for the nearly ten million Veterans of the five branches of the Armed Forces who served on active duty during the Vietnam era, nearly three million of whom served in the Vietnam theater. The Onslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial is one of the largest Vietnam Veterans Memorials in the nation and one of only a few that lists all the names of the fallen. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=599&quot;&gt;visit web page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/2014-09-11-Patriot-Day-9-11-Althouse-A3608.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2014-09-11-Patriot-Day-9-11-Althouse-A3608.jpg&quot; /&gt;9/11 Memorial Beam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 9/11 Memorial includes a beam from the Twin Towers, presented to the first troops to those who invaded Iraq from the police and firefighters of New York.  The Beam is located by the Beirut Memorial and Entry Wall to the Vietnam Veterans Memorial at Lejeune Memorial Gardens in Jacksonville. An annual Patriot Day Observance remembers those who lost theirs lives during the terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001 and those who continue to fight the war on terror. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=553&quot;&gt;visit web page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/MasterPlan1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beirut Memorial Master plan&quot; /&gt;Plans for the Future at Lejeune Memorial Gardens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens Master Plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans for the future include the Corpsman Memorial, Montford Point Memorial, Museum of the Marine and the Lejeune Greenway &amp;amp; Trail. The site also includes space for additional memorials. Click on the Map for a larger view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional Information please contact the City Manager’s Office at City Hall, 815 New Bridge Street, 910 938-5200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/corpsmenmemorialmodel-shapeimage_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Corpsmen Memorial Model&quot; /&gt;Corpsmen Memorial&lt;/strong&gt; - In February 2008, the Corpsmen Memorial Foundation was established with the goal of creating a monument in honor of Navy corpsmen who fought alongside their Marine brethren. The Corpsmen Memorial will be a life-sized replica of the clay sculpture currently housed in Naval Hospital Camp Lejeune, which portrays a Vietnam-era corpsman lying on top of a wounded Marine, whose right leg is in a makeshift splint, shielding him from impending danger. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funds have been accumulated over the past two and a half years, totaling nearly $30,000. The memorial is scheduled to be completed and placed in the Lejeune Memorial Gardens near Camp Johnson within the next two years, if the necessary funds are met. &lt;a href=&quot;http://nccorpsmenmemorial.net/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/montfordpointmemorial02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Montford Point Marine Memorial&quot; /&gt;Montford Point Marine Memorial&lt;/strong&gt; - President Barack Obama once said, “Despite being denied many basic rights, the Montford Point Marines committed to serve our country with selfless patriotism… Embodying the Marine Corps motto of Semper Fidelis, Always Faithful, these heroes paved the way for future generations of warriors, regardless of background, to serve in the finest military the world has ever known.” Funding is underway and a memorial to honor the Montford Point Marines is planned for Lejeune Memorial Gardens. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mpmamemorial.com/&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/rendering-museum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Museum of the Marine rendering&quot; /&gt;Museum of the Marine&lt;/strong&gt; - The Museum of the Marine is designed to pay tribute to the exceptional men and women, the Carolina Marines, whose training prepared them for service and leadership in the defense of our country and freedom worldwide. Within the walls of this 40,000-square-foot facility, we will tell the stories of the Carolina Marines, their units, bases and stations and epic battles, and of the Carolina communities that have supported them. Funding is underway for the museum that will be a wonderful addition to the Lejeune Memorial Gardens. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.museumofthemarine.org/&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens Greenway &amp;amp; Trail&lt;/strong&gt; - Following the transition of former railroad tracks into trails to the base, in 2007 the City won funds to begin work on a missing connector from downtown Jacksonville to the current pathway into Camp Lejeune at the point of the iconic pedestrian bridge over Lejeune Boulevard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Jacksonville Greenway Trail is installed it will be with reverence to all of the memorials within Lejeune Memorial Gardens.  The path is connection. It will connect the Civilian community of Jacksonville with the Military community of Camp Lejeune. It will connect the revitalized Downtown area with pedestrians both on foot and on bikes.  Most importantly the Jacksonville Greenway Trail is a connection to our past.  It will connect visitors to Lejeune Memorial Gardens and to those who have made the ultimate sacrifice in service to our Country.  It will connect future generations to the adversities overcome by the first black Marines at the Montford Point Marines Memorial and to the history of all who have served at the Museum of the Marine. The Jacksonville Greenway Trail will allow greater access for everyone to a site that preserves and honors the legacies of America’s finest. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=644&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 08:54:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/jacksonville/2014/11/21/gardens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/jacksonville/2014/11/21/gardens/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X feedly</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x-feedly&quot;&gt;Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X feedly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blackoctopus.net/2014/10/creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x-feedly/&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X feedly&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alex4d.com/notes/item/creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x&quot;&gt;Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
// &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alex4d.com/notes/item/creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x&quot;&gt;Final Cut Pro X and Post Production Blog – Alex4D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those iOS developers who want to provide more information to potential purchasers in the iOS app store, Apple suggest using video-based ‘app previews.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple have provided &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/app-previews/&quot;&gt; resources for developers&lt;/a&gt; who want to create app previews using iMovie 10.0.6 and Final Cut Pro X 10.1.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New in OS X Yosemite is the ability to record what happens on an iOS 8 device attached to your Mac. Here’s an excerpt from Apple’s instructions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;capture-screen-recordings-with-quicktime-player&quot;&gt;Capture Screen Recordings with QuickTime Player&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect your iOS device to your Mac using a Lightning cable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open QuickTime Player.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose File &amp;gt; New Movie Recording.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the window that appears, select your iOS device as the Camera and Microphone input source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1.wp.com/alex4d.com/images/alex4dNotes/2014/1024_AppPrev/AP-choose-iPhone-source.jpg?resize=371%2C181&quot; alt=&quot;AP-choose-iPhone-source&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you use the Record button, perform the actions on your iOS device that demonstrate the features of the app, you save the recording on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-cut-pro-x-app-preview-settings&quot;&gt;Final Cut Pro X app preview settings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/app-previews/final-cut-pro/Creating-App-Previews-with-Final-Cut-Pro-X.pdf&quot;&gt; PDF of instructions&lt;/a&gt; for those new to Final Cut Pro on how to create new projects and which custom size to use for each app preview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 5s, iPhone 5c, iPod touch 5th generation: 640 x 1136 for portrait, 1136 x 640 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 6: 750 x 1334 for portrait, 1334 x 750 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad Air, iPad 4th generation, iPad mini with Retina display: 900 x 1200 for portrait, 1200 x 900 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 6 Plus 1080 x 1920 for portrait, 1920 x 1080 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;App previews must be set to a frame rate of 30p.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;free-titles&quot;&gt;11 free titles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as the short PDF guide Apple also provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/app-previews/final-cut-pro/downloads/app-preview-titles.zip&quot;&gt; a set of free title plugins&lt;/a&gt; (12.2MB ZIP) to provide useful information in overlays on top of screen recordings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i2.wp.com/alex4d.com/images/alex4dNotes/2014/1024_AppPrev/APtitles-in-browser.jpg?resize=229%2C628&quot; alt=&quot;APtitles-in-browser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ZIP includes installation instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-market&quot;&gt;A new market?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For writer/editors, creating iOS app previews might become a marketable skill: “Sales for this app were low, but after using the services of &lt;em&gt;AppPreview4D&lt;/em&gt;, everything changed!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedly.com&quot;&gt;my feedly reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 09:53:45 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/ios/2014/10/29/iOS-App-Previews/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/ios/2014/10/29/iOS-App-Previews/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>icecast tutorial</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;icecast-and-darkice&quot;&gt;icecast and darkice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dzello.com/blog/2012/11/21/live-stream-audio-from-osx-mountain-lion-with-icecast-and-darkice&quot;&gt;ICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any team can benefit from a widely-accessible streaming music server. Sharing the same music increases team flow and builds &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/talk/play&quot;&gt;culture&lt;/a&gt;. And funny things happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share both music and announcements, &lt;a href=&quot;http://party.io&quot;&gt;party.io&lt;/a&gt; uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/play/play&quot;&gt;Play&lt;/a&gt; from Github. Play is an ‘employee-powered iTunes-based client-driven distributed music server for your office’. Our company DJ (a big-hearted, chrome-plated &lt;a href=&quot;http://hubot.github.com/&quot;&gt;hubot&lt;/a&gt;) manages Play and occasionally accepts submissions from the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play syncs the company song queue, but a streaming audio server is still needed to stream what’s playing. There are products that do this; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rogueamoeba.com/nicecast/&quot;&gt;Nicecast&lt;/a&gt; is one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also build an open-source frankenstack for free. It’s &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; four pieces: &lt;a href=&quot;http://cycling74.com/products/soundflower/&quot;&gt;Soundflower&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jackaudio.org/&quot;&gt;Jack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://darkice.org/&quot;&gt;Darkice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icecast.org/&quot;&gt;Icecast&lt;/a&gt;. This post explains how to put these pieces together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s a little more work, the outcome is the ability to stream &lt;strong&gt;system audio&lt;/strong&gt; anywhere. This makes more scenarios possible and it requires less maintenance - there’s no requirement to add media files in advance or to configure any applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can hear it, you can stream it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;before-starting&quot;&gt;Before starting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need the latest compiler installed, whether via XCode or the OSX Mountain Lion Command Line Tools installation at &lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.apple.com/&quot;&gt;http://connect.apple.com/&lt;/a&gt; (recommended if you don’t need all of XCode). You’ll need to be somewhat comfortable with working on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Beginning..._Was_the_Command_Line&quot;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure you have &lt;a href=&quot;http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; installed. And make sure to run &lt;code&gt;brew update&lt;/code&gt; before beginning, and &lt;code&gt;brew doctor&lt;/code&gt; if anything goes wrong along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-soundflower&quot;&gt;Installation: Soundflower&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soundflower is an inter-application audio routing utility. Soundflower creates additional audio devices that bind to applications to send and receive audio. Soundflower also comes with a program called Soundflowerbed. It lets you listen to audio locally even while broadcasting, like a splitter. Here’s what the Soundflowerbed menu bar app looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/soundflowerbed.png&quot; alt=&quot;Soundflowerbed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cycling74.com/soundflower-landing-page/&quot;&gt;Download Soundflower here&lt;/a&gt; and install it. Homebrew doesn’t have a Soundflower formula AFAIK, but thankfully there’s nothing tricky to this installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve restarted we’ll install the next component, Jack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-jack&quot;&gt;Installation: Jack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack is a professional quality audio tool that can also route audio between applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack had problems initially with Mac OSX 10.7.3+, but a beta version seems to have worked the bugs out. Neither the Homebrew formula nor the latest download on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jackosx.com/download.html&quot;&gt;jackosx.com&lt;/a&gt; have the new code, but you can find it on the Jack-OSX Yahoo group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a link to the 0.90b8 beta package on &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/jackosx/message/3945&quot;&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt;. Download and install it, restarting when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, start the Soundflowerbed app (in /Applications/Soundflower) and choose the ‘Audio Setup’ option from the menu bar icon it installs. This will launch the System Audio Midi Setup menu. Set both input and output to Soundflower (2ch), like in the image below. Also make sure the volume is up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/audiomidisetup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Audio Midi Setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we can start Jack as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;➜  ~  jackdmp -d coreaudio
jackdmp 1.9.9
Copyright 2001-2005 Paul Davis and others.
Copyright 2004-2012 Grame.
jackdmp comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY
This is free software, and you are welcome to redistribute it
under certain conditions; see the file COPYING for details
JACK server starting in realtime mode with priority 10
Input channel = 0 ==&amp;gt; JACK input port = 0
Input channel = 1 ==&amp;gt; JACK input port = 1
JACK output port = 0 ==&amp;gt; output channel = 0
JACK output port = 1 ==&amp;gt; output channel = 1
CoreAudio driver is running...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack will now be running and can pass audio from Soundflower into our next component, Darkice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-darkice&quot;&gt;Installation: Darkice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darkice is a live audio streamer. In our setup, it’s responsible for encoding the audio from Jack (into MP3, Ogg Vorbis, et. al.) and sending it to Icecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll install Darkice with Homebrew but this gets a little weird. Darkice has a dependency on Jack, but Homebrew doesn’t know we’ve already installed Jack through another means. So we have to install a ‘dummy’, unlinked Jack so Homebrew thinks the Jack dependency is satisfied but Darkice builds against the downloaded Jack and not the Homebrew Jack (this is essential).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


brew install darkice --use-llvm   #ignore the linking warnings for Jack - Darkice must complete without Jack linked!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this process Jack will fail to link and issue a warning but the script will still continue. This is good, because Darkice will then build against the downloaded Jack. If things blow up which installing dependencies, install without the llvm flag and then retry this again. The goal is just to get the Jack-failed-link and the Darkice build in the same step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-icecast&quot;&gt;Installation: Icecast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Icecast is the web-serving layer of our stack, accepting incoming client connections and then broadacsting out the stream it receives from Darkice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Icecast with Homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


brew install icecast
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;running-icecast-and-darkice&quot;&gt;Running Icecast and Darkice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a config file for Icecast: download this sample &lt;a href=&quot;/images/icecast.xml&quot;&gt;icecast.xml&lt;/a&gt; I’ve put together for this tutorial into &lt;code&gt;~/.icecast.xml&lt;/code&gt;. Now we can start Icecast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


icecast -c ~/.icecast.xml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need a config file for darkice: download this sample &lt;a href=&quot;/images/darkice.cfg&quot;&gt;darkice.cfg&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;code&gt;~/.darkice.cfg&lt;/code&gt;. Once you have it saved, let’s start Darkice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


darkice -c ~/.darkice.cfg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can now check our status by logging into Icecast’s administration UI. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8000/admin/&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8000/admin/&lt;/a&gt; and enter the admin-user and admin-password from the icecast.xml config file. You should arrive at the admin page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/icecast.png&quot; alt=&quot;Icecast Admin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you should see an area below that shows the active mount point, created by Darkice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dubspin.png&quot; alt=&quot;Icecast with Darkice mount&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;testing-with-a-client&quot;&gt;Testing with a client&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, head over to another computer on your network, or your smartphone, and head for to the streaming address we’ve set up. The URL should look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


http://computer.local:8000/spin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Substitute ‘computer.local’ for the hostname or IP address of your computer. ‘spin’ is the name of the mountpoint we specified in darkice.cfg (and 8000 the port).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paste the URL into Safari on Mac or iOS and you should get playback in iTunes / iOS Quicktime respectively:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/itunes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Streaming from iTunes&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/iphone.png&quot; alt=&quot;Streaming on iPhone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you, your team, or the whole Internet can listen to your music, broadcasts, and the output of the command &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/library/mac/#documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man1/say.1.html&quot;&gt;say&lt;/a&gt;! Flex the golden pipes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;configure-your-router&quot;&gt;Configure your router&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t be able to access your streaming server from outside your home network unless your open the appropriate ports on your router. In this example, you’d open port 8000. Your router’s instruction manual can you tell you how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bonus-gist&quot;&gt;Bonus Gist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get it all to work, you might want to run these programs in the background and on startup. I wrote up a few basic plist files to be used with launchd that do just that. You can find them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/4126599&quot;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creators of all of these fine tools. This article: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dudek.org/blog/140&quot;&gt;Broadcasting music to multiple speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 01:47:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/notes/2014/10/29/live-stream-audio-from-osx-mountain-lion-with-icecast-and-darkice/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/notes/2014/10/29/live-stream-audio-from-osx-mountain-lion-with-icecast-and-darkice/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Website part 1 of 6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/building-a-responsive-website-introduction/&quot;&gt;http://www.sitepoint.com/building-a-responsive-website-introduction/&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-introduction&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch: Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/42bd81912daf039b7faa53dbf9efcb25?s=96&amp;amp;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&amp;amp;r=G&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt;Annarita Tranfici&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published March 25, 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share?text=Build+a+Responsive%2C+Mobile-Friendly+Website+From+Scratch%3A+Introduction&amp;amp;via=sitepointdotcom&quot;&gt; __ Tweet &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://confirmsubscription.com/h/y/1FD5B523FA48AA2B&quot;&gt; Subscribe &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-entry-is-part-1-of-6-in-the-series-build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratchhttpwwwsitepointcomseriesbuild-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch&quot;&gt;This entry is part 1 of 6 in the series &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/series/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch/&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last series (“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/series/understanding-responsive-web-design/&quot;&gt;Understanding Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt;”), I defined the basic features of this new and important responsive approach to mobile-friendly, device-agnostic design. Now, let’s set the stage for a more concrete work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen that there are many aspects to take into consideration throughout the responsive design process: screen size, operating platform, user behavior, and so on. We have explored the various measurement options for fonts in a website, and we’ve covered the best way to approach &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/understanding-responsive-web-design-how-to-manage-fonts/&quot;&gt;typography&lt;/a&gt; in terms of responsive web design. We’ve explored the characteristics of four different &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/responsive-web-design-fluid-layouts/&quot;&gt;layout types&lt;/a&gt; and their respective fields of implementation. We’ve covered some common problems that a web designer may encounter when managing responsive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/understanding-responsive-web-design-how-to-manage-images/&quot;&gt;images&lt;/a&gt; (and pointed out potential solutions). Finally, we’ve explored the problem of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/understanding-responsive-web-design-cross-browser-compatibility/&quot;&gt;cross-browser compatibility&lt;/a&gt; and proposed different ways to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to demonstrate some &lt;strong&gt;real-world technical applications&lt;/strong&gt; of the responsive web design and build a real responsive website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objectives&quot;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with defining the objectives of this new series, and highlight what you’ll learn. Thanks to this tutorial…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll learn how to create a responsive design mockup, taking into account the main features of a website, the users’ needs, and the way to effectively combine responsive graphics and web design. The mockup of the website won’t be unique to one platform, and it’ll provide an example of the possible structure of a portal from several standpoints—imagining the view on three different devices: smartphones, tablets, and desktop PCs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll learn how to take full advantage of modern web technologies, namely HTML5 and CSS3, applying them step-by-step to each component of your web content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll see how to implement some rules related to responsive web design, by applying what we have analyzed conceptually in prior articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;media-queries&quot;&gt;Media Queries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the foundations or responsive design is &lt;strong&gt;media queries&lt;/strong&gt;, which ultimately make the site accessible and usable by the largest number of users, including those who do not use recent versions of popular browsers such as Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, and Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by getting our hands dirty with media queries; they represent one the most important tools that a web designer has to make their website responsive and mobile-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media queries are composed of &lt;strong&gt;two main parts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@ media screen&lt;/strong&gt; — The first part of a media query is the type of support. You might recognize this syntax from writing your own CSS styles, especially if you used this method before when designing printing options for your website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;min-width: 500px&lt;/strong&gt;) — The second part is the query itself. It includes the function to be evaluated (in this case, the minimum width of the browser window) and the corresponding value to test that the rule has been applied (in this case, a value of 500px).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about responsive web design, there is a tendency to focus exclusively on the width property, but there quite a few other attributes to consider when designing for a variety of screen sizes. There are many more valid properties associated with media queries. They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;width / height&lt;/strong&gt; — With these properties, you can set the width and height of the display area including any scroll bar. You can use the prefixes min and max.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;device-width/height&lt;/strong&gt; — These properties set the width and the height of the rendering surface, that is, the width and height of the entire screen of the device and not simply of the display area of the document. Even in this case, you can still use the min and max prefixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;orientation&lt;/strong&gt; — it sets a vertical or horizontal orientation. By specifying particular rules in the CSS stylesheet, you will be able to define how the various elements of a web page will be displayed on the device, in this case, depending on the orientation of the device we use. We can then specify the type of orientation; landscape and portrait that allow us to change the layout of your design according to the current orientation of the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aspect-ratio&lt;/strong&gt; — This is a property that sets the ratio between the width and height of the display of a document. Even in this case, you can &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; use the min and max prefixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;device-aspect-ratio&lt;/strong&gt; — This attribute monitors the ratio between the width and height of the device. Prefixes min and max are allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; — This applies certain CSS styles for all color devices. Prefixes min and max are allowed, but very few black and white devices (besides inexpensive Kindles) remain as popular browsing options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color-index&lt;/strong&gt; — This describes the number of colors in the palette supported by a device. It can have min and max prefixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;monochrome&lt;/strong&gt; — This property indicates the number of bits per pixel of a monochrome device (grayscale).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;resolution —&lt;/strong&gt; Resolution sets the resolution (i.e. the density of pixels) of the output device. The values ​​of the resolution can be expressed in DPI (dots per inch) or in DPCM (dots per centimeter).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scan&lt;/strong&gt; — a valid property for television screens that indicates the type of scan, interlaced or progressive. The values ​​can be precisely progressive or interlaced.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grid&lt;/strong&gt; — Grid indicates whether the device is a bitmap type or a “grid” equivalent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this short overview of the main (and often underutilized) properties of media queries, let’s proceed by pointing out what are the best responsive &lt;strong&gt;breakpoints&lt;/strong&gt; and how to determine them for a given project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakpoints in terms of responsive web design are browser widths that have a media query declaration to change the layout once the browser is within a declared width range. More specifically, a breakpoint is a point on a line that starts from 0, where there is a change (via CSS) within the layout of the page. Breakpoints are defined with numeric values ​​and units of measurement based on the media queries entered into your CSS stylesheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, every responsive website has a minimum of two breakpoints — one for tablets and one for mobile devices. Each breakpoint corresponds to a media query. In the media query below, I wrote CSS that only takes effect when the minimum width of the browser window (min-width) is equal to a specific value (that can be 320px, 480px, 768px, etc..).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of one of these standard breakpoints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@media only screen and (min-width : 320px) {

/* Styles */

}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, &lt;strong&gt;how many breakpoints does a web designer need to create?&lt;/strong&gt; This depends on the characteristics of the website, on its layout, and on the techniques that you decided to implement in order to turn your design plans into something truly interactive and responsive In essence, we could answer the previous question in this way: You need a breakpoint for every device that you deliberately choose to support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;breakpoints-according-to-the-devices&quot;&gt;Breakpoints According to the Devices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the prevailing practice tends to set breakpoints based on the size of the screen (or browser window) of the following popular device types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smartphone (with portrait or landscape orientation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tablet (with portrait or landscape orientation as well)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Netbook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop PC monitor with high or very high resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translating this scheme into pixels, you can see how for smartphone and tablet categories, the “standard” sizes adopted mainly correspond to the screen dimensions of the iPhone and iPad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;320px — iPhone in portrait orientation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;480px — iPhone in landscape orientation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;768px — iPad in portrait orientation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1024px — iPad in landscape orientation (as well as netbooks, since these devices typically have a horizontal resolution of 1024px).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone might argue that not all smartphones and tablets are iPhones or iPads, and they’d be unquestionably correct. But, in this case the screen size of the Apple device is used more as a reference point for a greater category of devices. Moreover, creating a breakpoint for each and every device would be totally absurd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good practice could be defining a set of main breakpoints possibly combined with some secondary breakpoints in order to fit the document to specific devices. You could also think about creating a custom breakpoint; this is very straightforward but requires a familiarity with media queries, so I suggest practicing initially with basic media queries and common breakpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s extremely important to test your dynamic layouts, including the breakpoints themselves, and the CSS that executes under certain screen size conditions. If you do not have both of those aspects of your responsive design in good order, you’ll end up with glaring layout and functionality problems that make your website less responsive than if you hadn’t attempted any mobile-friendly accommodations. Test your designs thoroughly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have introduced the main objectives of the series, and above all, I have given a short but complete introduction on the critical components of media queries and responsive breakpoints. In the next article, I’ll start with the planning and the creation of a mockup for each of the three main device types on which our website will be designed, tested, and displayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to learn more about Responsive Web Design? Check out SitePoint’s new book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/books/responsive1/&quot;&gt;Jump Start Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/42bd81912daf039b7faa53dbf9efcb25?s=96&amp;amp;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&amp;amp;r=G&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt;Annarita Tranfici&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a Bachelor’s degree in European languages, cultures, and literature from the University of Naples. I’m passionate about graphics and web design, and for several years I’ve been working on projects and designs for many companies. I’m a writer for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ug.audero.it/&quot;&gt;Audero User Group&lt;/a&gt;; my specialties are HTML, CSS, Web Design, and Adobe Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-might-also-like&quot;&gt;You might also like:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/jechessa/&quot;&gt;Joyce Echessa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feb 10, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2sis3lil8ndrq.cloudfront.net/books/jshtml-basics1_medium_3d.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab a free copy of one our latest ebooks! Packed with hints and tips on HTML5’s most powerful new features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 12:31:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scratch Site part 4 of 6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-css-stylesheet/&quot;&gt;http://www.sitepoint.com/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-css-stylesheet/&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-css-stylesheet&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch: CSS stylesheet&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/42bd81912daf039b7faa53dbf9efcb25?s=96&amp;amp;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&amp;amp;r=G&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt;Annarita Tranfici&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published May 7, 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share?text=Build+a+Responsive%2C+Mobile-Friendly+Website+From+Scratch%3A+CSS+stylesheet&amp;amp;via=sitepointdotcom&quot;&gt; __ Tweet &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://confirmsubscription.com/h/y/1FD5B523FA48AA2B&quot;&gt; Subscribe &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entry is part 4 of 6 in the series &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/series/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch/&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last article of this series, I’ve shown how to start building a website from scratch with a particular focus on the HTML code and its main elements. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to introduce the first CSS rules in order to have a general idea of the graphic style that the homepage of our website will display, especially for the pc-desktop version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, before having a look on the rules we have to apply in order to create a particular design for our homepage, let’s see how it will appear in our browser window (my default browser is Chrome but, with the application of some specific rules, you’ll be able to obtain the same result for all modern web-browsers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homepage of our totally customizable website should look more or less as following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dab1nmslvvntp.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/website-screenshot-desktop-version.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dab1nmslvvntp.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/website-screenshot-desktop-version-1024x910.png&quot; alt=&quot;website-screenshot-desktop-version&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As you can see, I have imagined a very big banner to allow the designer to express all his creativity and chosen colors that combine in a clear and positive way (I really love them!). Having said that, let’s dive deep into the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the HTML section, in this case we’ll proceed step-by-step from the upper part of our layout to the bottom part. The code for the very first part (which includes the elements of banner, newsletter bar and menu) will be shown piece after piece with a very short comment, as for the other items of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one is the banner element, with this code for styling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#banner
{
   width: 100%;
   margin-top: 0.2em;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These first rules simple enough to understand. To space the banner from the top of the browser window we’re applying a margin of 0.2em and to let our banner-image cover all the width of our browser’s window, we’ve set the corresponding rule with a percentage of 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go on with the rules for styling our newsletter-box. In this case we have to pay attention for the rules to put on the id and the ones to consider for the class since I have decided, for personal clarity, to not choose different names for elements that substantially indicate the same part. So, for the class we set a background color (which will be the color of the box and a margin-top of 0.2 em-you’ll find out why it’s better to use these kind of measurements for a responsive website in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/understanding-responsive-web-design-how-to-manage-fonts/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article, which will give you a short overview on the most common units used in Web Design) to slightly space the newsletter-box from the banner above. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The id “newsletter-box”, that is the space where we’ll find the input field and the submit button, has three simple rules, to define the spacing with the box that contains the above-mentioned elements. As you can see, there’s an id (“mobile-newsletter-box”) that seems to be inappropriate to the version we’re analysing. Actually, it’s not so: since there’ll be a change of view when passing from a pc-desktop version to a tablet version or a mobile-phone one, we have to “suggest” to our stylesheet how to perform and display the page elements. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, as you’ll see in the next article when we’ll discuss about the rules to set thinking responsively, the disposition of all the elements characterizing the newsletter bar will totally change. What we have to do now is avoid having the mobile-display shown in the pc-desktop version. To achieve this result, we simply set to the rule “display” the none parameter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nice effect I’d like to talk about is the transition I have applied to the white box where the user inserts his e-mail to receive news. Setting to the element a transition, the resulting effect is an enlargement of the box; the other thing I’ve done is to indicate the time that this has to last. This is a CSS3 rule that creates a simple and light movement with a very pleasant output. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last rule to discuss is the width applied when the newsletter box is clicked: setting this to 17em, the box will appear larger than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.newsletter-box
{
   background-color: #c32526;
   margin-top: 0.2em;
}

#newsletter-box
{
   margin-top: 0.5em;
   height: 1.8em;
   padding: 0.3em;
}

#mobile-newsletter-box
{
   display: none;
}

#newsletter-email
{
   width: 12em;
   -webkit-transition: all 1s;
   -moz-transition: width 1s;
   -o-transition: width 1s;
   -ms-transition: width 1s;
   transition: width 1s;
}

#newsletter-email:focus
{
   width: 17em;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go on now analyzing our navigation bar. To delete the default bullet points of our menu list, we set the parameter to none, while to center it we recourse to the well-known rule “text-align: center”. Then we change the padding and the margin rules to the size that seems to be appropriate for our purpose. To let the elements of the list appear one after another horizontally, we change the display from the default setting “block” to “inline” and also, in this case, specify the margin parameters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s time to have a look at the rules applied to the link elements: as font, I’ve chosen “Bebas Neue” (you can download it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dafont.com/bebas-neue.font&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I’ve set a font-size of 1.3 em, removed the underlining with the rule “text-decoration: none” and set the color I preferred. This color changes when the cursor moves on the menu items and, moreover, when the user clicks on the link of the page he desires to visit, there’s a 3D effect, and you can obtain it setting the rule “position: relative” on the menu links and the parameters top and left on the active state of the same element. In this way, you’ll have a slight movement that will give you the impression of a clickable 3D button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ul.menu-list
{
   list-style-type: none;
   padding: 0;
   margin: 1em 0em;
   text-align: center;
}

li.menu-item
{
   display: inline;
   margin: 0em 1.5em;
}

a.menu-item-link
{
   font-family: &amp;amp;amp;quot;Bebas Neue&amp;amp;amp;quot;,Calibri,Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;
   font-size: 1.3em;
   text-decoration: none;
   color: #c31f05;
position: relative;

}

a.menu-item-link:hover
{
   color: #000000;
}

a.menu-item-link:active
{
   top: 0.1em;
   left: 0.1em;
}

#menu-select
{
   display: none;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, move on to the general part, that is on the rules applied to elements such as heading, paragraphs, images, boxes appearance and so on. Here is the code with the specifications of the rules for the layout I have thought out, planned and realized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body
{
   max-width: 1024px;
   margin: 0 auto;
   font-family: &amp;amp;amp;quot;Cwmagic&amp;amp;amp;quot;,Calibri,Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;
   background-color: #E3E3E3;
   font-size: 1.2em;
   line-height: 1.5em;
}

img
{
   border: 0em;
}

h1,
h2,
h3
{
   text-align: center;
}

.float-left
{
   float: left;
}

.float-right
{
   float: right;
}

.clear-both
{
   clear: both;
}

.shadow
{
   -webkit-box-shadow: 0.4em 0.4em 0.2em #5C5B5B;
   -moz-box-shadow: 0.4em 0.4em 0.2em #5C5B5B;
   -o-box-shadow: 0.4em 0.4em 0.2em #5C5B5B;
   -ms-box-shadow: 0.4em 0.4em 0.2em #5C5B5B;
   box-shadow: 0.4em 0.4em 0.2em #5C5B5B;
   margin-right: 0.4em !important;
}

.long-box,
.small-box
{
   background-color: #cdcdcd;
   padding: 0em 0.3em;
   margin: 0em;
   margin-bottom: 1em;
}

.small-box
{
   width: 47%;
}

p
{
   margin-top: 0;
   margin-bottom: 0.5em;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t explain the rules one by one as for the first part, especially because they are almost all the same. The only thing to which I’d like you’d pay attention is the classes float left, float right and clear both; in fact, I’ve preferred to create a class which “identifies” these rules and applies them to the elements in the HTML code rather than repeating the elements. Another element worthy of note is the CSS3 rule “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.css3.info/preview/box-shadow/&quot;&gt;shadow&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This property allows designers to easily implement multiple drop shadows (outer or inner) on box elements, specifying values for color, size, blur and offset.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It can accept a comma-separated list of shadows, each defined by 2-4 length values (specifying in order the horizontal offset, vertical offset, optional blur distance and optional spread distance of the shadow), an optional color value and an optional ‘inset‘ keyword (to create an inner shadow, rather than the default outer shadow).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Browser support is growing of late with Mozilla (Firefox), Webkit (Safari/Chrome/Konqueror), Opera and the IE9 Platform Preview all offering a decent implementation of the specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s conclude this article with the rules applied to elements present in the footer, that is the footer itself and the bar containing the icons for the linking to the most important social networks’ profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#main-footer
{
   background-color: #c32526;
   text-align: center;
}

.social-bar a
{
   text-decoration: none;
   margin-right: 3em;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let’s see how to manage fonts in the CSS stylesheet, bearing in mind that Internet Explorer requires a different format for the fonts, that is “eot”. Here is the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/*
 ***********************************
     FONT FOR INTERNET EXPLORER
 ***********************************
*/
@font-face
{
   font-family: &amp;amp;amp;quot;Bebas Neue&amp;amp;amp;quot;;
   src: url(../css/bebasneue.eot);
}

@font-face
{
   font-family: &amp;amp;amp;quot;Palatino Linotype&amp;amp;amp;quot;;
   src: url(../css/pala.eot);
}
/*
 ***********************************
       FONT FOR OTHER BROWSERS
 ***********************************
*/
@font-face
{
   font-family: &amp;amp;amp;quot;Bebas Neue&amp;amp;amp;quot;;
   src:
      local(&amp;amp;amp;quot;Bebas Neue&amp;amp;amp;quot;),
      local(&amp;amp;amp;quot;Bebas Neue&amp;amp;amp;quot;),
      url(&amp;amp;amp;quot;../css/bebasneue.ttf&amp;amp;amp;quot;);
}

@font-face
{
   font-family: &amp;amp;amp;quot;Palatino Linotype&amp;amp;amp;quot;;
   src:
      local(&amp;amp;amp;quot;Palatino Linotype&amp;amp;amp;quot;),
      local(&amp;amp;amp;quot;Palatino Linotype&amp;amp;amp;quot;),
      url(&amp;amp;amp;quot;../css/pala.ttf&amp;amp;amp;quot;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article we’ve seen the basic rules to create a simple layout for a website. After concentrating on the pc-desktop version, in the next part we’ll see which are the rules to apply to make this layout responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/42bd81912daf039b7faa53dbf9efcb25?s=96&amp;amp;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&amp;amp;r=G&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt;Annarita Tranfici&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a Bachelor’s degree in European languages, cultures, and literature from the University of Naples. I’m passionate about graphics and web design, and for several years I’ve been working on projects and designs for many companies. I’m a writer for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ug.audero.it/&quot;&gt;Audero User Group&lt;/a&gt;; my specialties are HTML, CSS, Web Design, and Adobe Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-might-also-like&quot;&gt;You might also like:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/jraj/&quot;&gt;Jay Raj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aug 20, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/author/russweakley/&quot;&gt;Russ Weakley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/jaccob/&quot;&gt;Jacco Blankenspoor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jun 24, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2sis3lil8ndrq.cloudfront.net/books/jshtml-basics1_medium_3d.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab a free copy of one our latest ebooks! Packed with hints and tips on HTML5’s most powerful new features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 12:21:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/web/2014/10/16/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-css-stylesheet.txt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/web/2014/10/16/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-css-stylesheet.txt/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Setup a Mix Minus</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-setup-a-mix-minus-for-recording-skype&quot;&gt;How to Setup a Mix Minus for Recording Skype&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/how-to-setup-a-mix-minus/&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to How to Setup a Mix Minus for Recording Skype&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?s=100&amp;amp;p[url]=http://thepodcastersstudio.com/how-to-setup-a-mix-minus/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-social-ring/includes/../admin/images/sr-fb-share.png&quot; alt=&quot;Share&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to record Skype calls for your podcast interviews? This is how you do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scroll down to see a complete photo walkthrough and description of the steps demonstrated in this video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recording a Skype conversation or any other VOIP program on your computer using professional (XLR) microphones with the ability to mix in other sounds all without having the person on Skype get a feedback loop of their own voice, requires you to setup a mix minus with your audio mixer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic concept is you want to mix all your audio inside your mixer which includes you Skype caller then send that audio back out to Skype minus (without) the Skype callers voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this you need a mixer with Aux sends. This is a specialized output on your mixer that allows you to select which audio sources coming into the mixer get sent back out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this video we are using the Aux B (post-fader) to send our microphone and a soundboard with sound effects (FX) back to Skype. Post fader simply means that our Aux send goes through the main channel fader before getting sent out of the Auxiliary port. In this case, we must turn up both the Aux B send fader and the corresponding channel’s main volume fader in order for Skype to hear the audio. If we were using Aux A (pre-fader) then the main channel fader would have no effect on our audio leaving the mixer via the Aux send for each channel we are sending audio out of the Aux A output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would you choose a pre over post fader and vice versa? If you were recording your mix to an audio recorder as seen in this video, we could use Aux A (pre-fader) to send audio to Skype without being affected by each channel’s main fader so that we could use different audio levels to go to Skype than we are sending to our recording.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Aux B (post-fader) would allow us to easily control what level of audio Skype gets by simply adjusting the main channel fader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this video the setup is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My microphone (Heil PR40) is plugged into channel 1 via XLR cable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My iPhone is plugged into channel 5/6 via a stereo 3.5mm to Y cable (1/4″ left and right) for sending sound FX into the mixer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My computer (Skype) is plugged into channel 7/8 coming from my computer’s headphone output using another stereo 3.5mm to Y cable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mixer is sending audio to the computer (Skype) via Aux B using a 1/4″ to 3.5mm stereo cable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve the mix-minus setup, the Aux B fader on my microphone’s channel as well as my iPhone’s channel is turned up (set your fader at whatever level is good for Skype. I like my Skype audio meter to hit about 70 to 75%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aux B fader on my computers channel (7/8) is left in the off position or turned all the way down so that no audio is going out of the aux send. This is the minus part of your mix-minus. All the audio in the mix is going out to Skype through the Aux sends, minus the Skype caller’s audio on 7/8. If we had this Aux send turned up then the person on Skype would hear their own voice back because we would be sending it back to them after it came into the mixer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this video’s setup, each channel that we are sending audio out of the Aux B must also have its main channel fader turned up as well or else the audio won’t leave through the Aux because we are using a post-fader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s much more complex sounding that it really is. Take your time and walk through each step. Skype has a test calling service in your contact list that will allow you to make a call and receive audio back so that you can test your setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-by-step-mix-minus-walkthrough-with-photos&quot;&gt;Step by Step Mix-Minus Walkthrough with Photos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;key--red-arrows--cable-yellow-box--mixer-input-blue-box--mixer-controls&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;KEY** – &lt;strong&gt;Red Arrows&lt;/strong&gt; = cable, &lt;strong&gt;Yellow Box&lt;/strong&gt; = mixer input, &lt;strong&gt;Blue Box&lt;/strong&gt; = Mixer Controls&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1 – Mixer Requirements and Cabling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a proper mix-minus setup you need a mixer with an “Auxiliary (Aux) Send” (yellow box in image). This channel allows you to choose which individual channels get sent out of your mixer (blue boxes in image). For a mix-minus, we’ll be sending all of our audio in our mix, &lt;strong&gt;minus&lt;/strong&gt; the channel that has Skype on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Step-1-mixer_with_aux_send-600x400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 1 Mixer with Aux Send&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The yellow box in this first image (above) shows you where the AUX SENDS are located on my particular mixer. You see that this mixer has two (A (pre), B (post)). Your mixer needs at least one Auxiliary send in order to properly setup a mix-minus. The more Aux’s you have the more separate instances of Skype you can include in your mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that many mixers label the Auxiliary Send channel differently. For example, my Mackie ProFX12 labels them as Mon (monitor) Send and FX Send. Depending on what mixer you are using, they may be called something else but a quick check at the specs should tell you how many Aux Sends your mixer or the one you plan to buy has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the blue box you see the controls for the Aux Send channels for each individual channel on this mixer. This is where you will set the amount of volume that comes out of the Aux Send channel for each channel on your mixer including sending NO audio (level all the way down/off) on the channel that has Skype coming into the mixer. Remember, this is called a mix-minus because you are sending the “mix” of all your audio coming into the mixer back out to Skype, “minus” the Skype audio. This prevents the person on Skype hearing their own voice back causing a feedback loop. I’ll explain later why you might want to use a “pre” or “post” fader which on this mixer is labeled Aux A and B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cabling&lt;/strong&gt; – Mike Phillips (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mcphillips&quot; title=&quot;Mike Phillips on twitter&quot;&gt;@McPhillips&lt;/a&gt;) wrote an excellent article on choosing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibroadcastnetwork.org/blog/interfacing-skype-with-a-mixer&quot;&gt;best cables for setting up a mix-minus with your computer&lt;/a&gt;. The cables recommended by Mike can be seen in the following images. The cables you see in the video above are fine but as Mike points out, anytime you use a adapter (i.e. 1/8″ to 1/4″) you create another point of potential failure. I’ve never had any issue with the cabling you see in the video but why not start with the best and take Mike’s (expert) advice when it comes to selecting the proper cables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cables you’ll see in this walkthrough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2 – Plug in the Microphone(s) and Get Initial Levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Step-2-plug_in_mic_set_level-600x400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 2 - Plug in Mic and Set an Initial Level&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you see I’ve plugged in my microphone (Heil PR40) to channel 1 using an XLR cable. I’ve turned the gain knob (first blue box below the mic input on the mixer) to its center position and the fader for channel 1 (lowest blue box on channel 1) to the center as well. I’ve also turned the fader for the “Main Mix” (blue box on far right, bottom) to the middle position. This knob controls the overall level of all the audio that is feeding into the mixer. These levels are just an initial setting to make sure I’m getting audio from the microphone into the mixer. Simply talk into the mic and see if you are registering levels on your mixer’s LED audio meter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more than one microphone, repeat this step as outlined above. You can see on this mixer I can plug in three more XLR microphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Step 3 Plug in Aux Send Cable to Mixer and Computer Input&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/step-3-merged-600x400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 3 - Plug Aux Send into the Computer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to take a cable out of your mixer’s auxiliary send channel and plug that into your computer. This will be how Skype will receive the audio coming from your mixer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the picture above you see the red arrow points to the type of cable you want to use. Referring to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibroadcastnetwork.org/blog/interfacing-skype-with-a-mixer&quot; title=&quot;Interfacing Skype with a Mixer&quot;&gt;Mike’s article on cabling for a mix-minus&lt;/a&gt; it’s important to note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Most Internet broadcasters and podcasters are (or should be) using an auxiliary send on the mixer to send a mix-minus feed to Skype. That feed is mono. Most desktop and USB computer sound cards have stereo inputs. Skype really only looks at the left channel for its input, but some cheap, no-name sound cards may actually get the channels reversed internally. Therefore, it’s a good idea to feed to audio from the aux send on the mixer to both the left and right channels of the computer sound card.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; A good solution is to use the Hosa CMP-105 cable, pictured here. The CMP-105 has a 1/8 inch TRS plug on one end and a ¼ inch TS plug on the other. The tip of the ¼ inch plug is connected to the tip and ring of the 1/8 inch TRS plug. The ¼ inch mono plug connects to the mixer’s aux out jack, and the 1/8 inch plug connects to the computer sound card. Even though Skype is mono and only sees the left channel of the audio input, the CMP-105 causes audio to appear on both the left and right inputs of the computer sound card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this setup, I’m using the Aux B or Post Fader on the mixer to send audio to the computer. See the “advanced settings” section below for reasons why you might want to use either Aux A (pre) or Aux B (post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you’ll notice that the input to the computer is being handed by a device called an “iMic” made by Griffin. This is an analog to digital converter which takes the 3.5mm input (seen here plugged into the “in”) and converts it to a digital signal which is taken into the computer via USB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your computer doesn’t have a 3.5mm microphone input (e.g. Apple Macbook Pro models later than 2011) then you’ll need a device like this to input your audio to the computer from the mixer. When you setup your Skype audio preferences, you’ll want to select this device as your “microphone input.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4 – Plug the (Skype) Computer into the Mixer &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Output-from-Computer-to-Mixer-merged1-640x426.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Output from Computer to Mixer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 5 (optional) – Plug in a Soundboard or Additional Audio to the Mixer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Soundboard-to-Mixer-640x426.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Soundboard to Mixer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have another source of audio such as a soundboard with music and effects, listener feedback, or any audio from another computer/device, then you can use one of your remaining open channels to bring in those sounds. In the picture above you see I’ve inputed an iPhone using a CMP-159 ?” stereo to ¼” dual mono cable. I’m using one of my remaining stereo channels because the app I’m using as a soundboard (Bossjock for iOS) will be bringing in stereo audio such as music and sound FX. If you are bringing in a mono source such as voice, you can use one of your remaining mono inputs (1/4″ plugs below the XLR inputs) and only plug the left channel ¼” mono plug (gray lead labeled “Tip”) into the mixer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see I once again set an initial level (blue box on channel 5/6) to confirm I’m receiving audio from the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 6 Plug in an Audio Recorder to the Mixer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Step-6-plug_in_recorder-640x426.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 6 plug in audio recorder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we get to the final step in this setup which is plugging in an audio recorder so we can record our Skype call/podcast. Check the “alternative setups” section below to see how you would wire this setup if you wanted to record into your computer. If you do chose to record into a computer, I still strongly suggest getting an audio recorder to record into as a backup. This way if your recording software or computer crashes, you won’t lose your interview. It can be really painful to be 20, 30, 60 minutes into an interview only to lose it because your software decided to crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the picture above I’m using a 1/8″ stereo plug to dual RCA and outputting the mixer’s audio through the “Tape Out” output. This will capture a recording of all the audio going into your mixer including the person on Skype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alternative-setups&quot;&gt;Alternative Setups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Record to separate channels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thepodcastersstudio.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Advanced-panning_channels-600x380.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Advanced-panning_channels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a mixer that has either a FireWire or USB2.0 or higher output, you can record all the channels your mixer provides on separate tracks inside audio recording software that supports it. However, most mixers do not have these types of connections. When you only have a stereo mix out of your mixer how do you record audio on separate channels? Panning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to understand here that because you don’t have FireWire or USB2.0, you can only achieve two separate channels. However for many podcasters this will be enough because it’s just you, the interviewer and Skype, the interviewee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice in the image above that channel 1 and channel 7/8 have their “pan” knobs turned all the way left and right respectively. Because you are sending a stereo mix (2 channels on a single track) to your audio recording software, you can create two separate channels with the left side of the stereo track containing audio that you panned to the left and the right side containing all the audio you panned to the right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above image, my microphone on channel one will be on the left side of the stereo track and the Skype caller on channel 7/8 will be on the right side of the stereo track. The resulting audio file will look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you begin to edit your audio, you can break apart this stereo track creating two separate mono tracks each containing only the audio that was placed on each track as a result of using the pan knobs. Now I have much more control over my audio in the editing process because my Skype caller’s voice is not mixed with my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of what this allows you to do in the edit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply different effects to each audio track&lt;/strong&gt; – Each person’s voice will be different from the other. When adding effects such as EQ, Compression, Gates, Denoisers, etc. you’ll want each person to have their own unique recipe of effects. By having yourself on one track and you Skype caller on the other, you can handle how each track is processed separately.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove unwanted sounds&lt;/strong&gt; – Your interviewee might cough while you’re talking and you’ll want to remove that. Having them on their own track will allow you to remove any part of their audio without affecting your own. If you recorded a stereo mix with panning your two channels, that cough could not be removed without also removing your own audio.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating cleaner audio&lt;/strong&gt; – My audio editing workflow consists of removing the parts of an audio track where there is no talking. For example, if I’m asking a question and the interviewee is just listening, I remove that part of their audio. This also removes the noise floor (hiss) from their track thus making the overall mix cleaner. There are other ways to accomplish this such as inserting silence or using noise gates but for me this is the most effective workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix crosstalk&lt;/strong&gt; – If your guest speaks at the same time as you are speaking it can cause both or one of the person’s audio to get lost in the crosstalk. This always seems to be the case just as someone has made their most important point. Having each person on their own track allows you to shift the two pieces of audio on the timeline thus allowing each person to be heard. This is an incredibility powerful tool to have as an editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Recording into the same computer that’s running Skype – **if you want or need to record your audio back into the same computer you are using for Skype, simply run another feed out of your mixer to your audio recording software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for example, you can take the Main Mix out of the mixer and input that into your computer (using a separate soundcard/input on your computer) and use that feed to record into software on the same computer. This feed will contain all the audio including the Skype callers voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Recording with two computers – **coming soon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advanced-settings&quot;&gt;Advanced settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre vs Post Fader -&lt;/strong&gt; coming soon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Gear used to make this video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*all links should be considered affiliates. Purchases made using these links help support this website. Please read my ethics statement at http://thepodcastersstudio.com/ethics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:59:10 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/podcasting/2014/10/15/How%20to%20Setup%20a%20Mix%20Minus/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/podcasting/2014/10/15/How%20to%20Setup%20a%20Mix%20Minus/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Final Cut Pro X | Organized</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thefcpxeditor.tumblr.com/post/99595525563/fcp-x-quick-tip-organize-at-high-speed&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to The Final Cut Pro X Editor • FCP X Quick Tip: Organize at High Speed&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-final-cut-pro-x-editor--fcp-x-quick-tip-organize-at-high-speed&quot;&gt;The Final Cut Pro X Editor • FCP X Quick Tip: Organize at High Speed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fcp-x-quick-tip-organize-at-high-speed&quot;&gt;FCP X Quick Tip: Organize at High Speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/fb7c9c09b7f22cedb3ceb49f5910415c/tumblr_inline_nd6tjjalff1r4py0o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Braden Storrs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an editor I’d rather be editing then doing all the preparation work that leads to it. I’d say most of us don’t have an assistant editor to do all the tedious work so if there’s any way to speed up the process then bring it on! This tip will especial help those working on any kind of larger project such as a documentary or film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This technique is similar to one I used in earlier versions of FCP X with Keyword collections but it much smarter to use with Smart Collections (go figure). MacBreak Studio did a video on this last year called &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/gLPnK_vvk0w&quot;&gt;Smarter Smart Collections&lt;/a&gt;, but it was before the FCP X Library model so I thought I’d put this together with the current workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart Collections let you organize your media, based on sets of rules, into any number of collections you would like to create. If you are creating these collections new for every project you do then you are wasting a lot of time you could be saving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new Library and save it somewhere on your Mac’s hard drive so it is always accessible, or wherever you deem appropriate. I call mine Library Template:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/5e5cd367abe0ed69ddf2cf21389fe436/tumblr_inline_nd6tzeuqFe1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I rename the default Event to Event Template:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/5e32702651a04dcd986dcc7e3b52167c/tumblr_inline_nd6u6c5sJH1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then create two folders for use in the project. A Smart Collections Folder and a Keyword Collections Folder. This isn’t required, it just keeps things tidy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/d036676b36ca5236f5af38b83830389b/tumblr_inline_nd6u96FerK1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point start creating your Smart Collections and place them in the Smart Collections folder. You can right click on the Event and select “New Smart Collection” or use the keyboard shortcut Option+Command+N:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/67e38ba5ffc7f802296388c7258ae8d7/tumblr_inline_nd6ue87yKG1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rename the Smart Collection to what it will represent (i.e. multicam clips, dialogue, music, compound clips, notes, unused video, etc.). Here’s the collections I’ve created that include most of the collections I might want while editing. Your list will probably be different. Just suit it to your needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/ea51353c07be2b5ac1ae48885cc79f01/tumblr_inline_nd6ujvVL4c1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point double click on each of the Smart Collections and give them the appropriate set of rules to match the category. Don’t forget to do this. The collections won’t figure this out on their own. For Example, here is the rule set for the Dialogue collection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/27281c33da39354dfb8e01a3bffed3ab/tumblr_inline_nd6uo4ycLm1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to Keyword Collections, they are harder to predetermine. They are extremely useful but are more project specific. So generally they are added after the media is imported. They are useful for separating out takes from certain actors, scenes, script pages, etc, for example. If there are certain Keyword Collections you know you’ll need on every project, outside of the Smart Collections, create them now. Then when the media is imported, apply the Keywords to the appropriate media. Here are two videos that show how useful Keywords can be. &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/vyLTMgtE_PY&quot;&gt;Lightiron: Live Play 3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/pmHwME_sK30?list=UUnqmgMi2D6KQdFKGq0kKkdQ&quot;&gt;FCP X at the Studio Level&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/0079d03755d78735c497354c1811c96a/tumblr_inline_nd7078T5fJ1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even use Keywords to create a specific Smart Collection based on certain Keywords:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/918c8afba0799a090f159252319cac10/tumblr_inline_nd70g4gTrz1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in any case, just customize it to your needs. There’s enough tools in there to fine tune your collections to an almost ridiculous level. It may take a little bit of time to set this up, but once you do you never have to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a new project go ahead and load the Template Library. Then create and save the new Library for your project. It will have a blank Event in it that you can delete later if you don’t want it. Then just grab your Event Template and drag it to the new library and drop it on it. Follow the prompt and there you go, all of your organization is now applied to the new Library and as you import media the files will all be automatically sorted to the proper collections. Pretty awesome. At this point rename the Event Template in the new Library to whatever is appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/d231a8f734a4a3490b91984864a3226a/tumblr_inline_nd75qzGJj11r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/70176d30be2b07178b9895ec9b4db075/tumblr_inline_nd75rdg0wr1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/15830691b0b27191c9d8e9c35b7390a0/tumblr_inline_nd75rqgsuA1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also drag the Keyword or Smart Collections between events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/48693b076e00ef5cf013ecb87d1192f0/tumblr_inline_nd75ywjeZo1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/8680eb7f56bd1986d4e8d7ccaa514b8b/tumblr_inline_nd75z7pbQi1r4py0o.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point you can close your Library Template and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just took you 30 seconds to organize hundreds or even thousands of files when it could have taken you hours to do it manually. Got to love that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This article was written with FCP X being at version 10.1.3. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** The article’s title piece was created with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motionvfx.com/mplugs-33.html#1&quot;&gt;mObject&lt;/a&gt; from Motion VFX in Motion 5.1.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 19:01:07 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/fcp/2014/10/09/Final%20Cut%20Pro%20X%20organization/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/fcp/2014/10/09/Final%20Cut%20Pro%20X%20organization/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to copy keyframes in Motion on MacBreak Studio</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-copy-keyframes-in-motion-on-macbreak-studio&quot;&gt;How to copy keyframes in Motion on MacBreak Studio&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fcp.co/motion/tutorials-for-apple-motion/1093-how-to-copy-keyframes-in-motion-on-macbreak-studio&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It might be NAB time, but Steve and Mark are still cranking out the tutorials. This week they look at how to copy keyframes in Motion.Slightly ironic that we post this tutorial today as we had the great pleasure of spending time with Steve and Mark last night at the Motion Media Ball and then the Adobe party afterwards. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This morning we were also treated to a great breakfast at The Wynn from Ripple Training with a whole host of great people from the FCP ecosystem.So no secret that this episode of MacBreak Studio was recorded a while ago back in Petaluma! This time Mark Spencer shows Steve Martin how to copy keyframes in Apple’s Motion5. If behaviors just won’t cut it for an animation then keyframing may be the answer. If so, you’ll probably need to be able to know how to copy them too.Great stuff from the duo and we hope to see them at the SuperMeet tonight.
If you would like to more about Motion, Mark has some excellent tutorials on the Ripple Training website.     	&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 10:31:34 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/motion/2014/10/05/Motion%20Keyframes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/motion/2014/10/05/Motion%20Keyframes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Final Cut Pro X and Dropbox Part 3 - Summary of Results</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My experiment with using Final Cut Pro X and Dropbox as a collaborative tool has yielded some educational results.  I have learned how a SparseDisk segments it’s innards revealing its (dir) nature. I also see some potential and sure fire ways to get hurt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The few snafus along the way have not necessarily been a dropbox nor FCP issue &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt;, it was how these programs work with there own files.  If the project has compound clips created within it, the new version of Final Cut Pro X now a adds said compound to your events. I don’t know exactly where this compound lives. (at this time I think it resides in the &lt;strong&gt;render files&lt;/strong&gt; folder)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;restoring&quot;&gt;Restoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The restorative properties of dropbox As it applies to a Sparse disk file.
I had a theory that whatever changes I made in the DB folder would be able to roll back in time much like other files in the DB universe. I was wrong. Seem that sparsedisk is seen as a &lt;em&gt;Folder&lt;/em&gt; to dropbox. Thus a previous state doesn’t exist. (TimeMachine can if needed)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compound-clips&quot;&gt;Compound Clips&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 17:54:43 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/final/cut/pro/x/2014/10/03/Collaborative%20Final%20Cut%20Pro%20X/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/final/cut/pro/x/2014/10/03/Collaborative%20Final%20Cut%20Pro%20X/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Podcast mind map podcast</title>
        <description>
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;layout: post
title:  “Skype call recording with bookmarked, mind-mapped notes”
date:   2014-10-05 14:26:54
categories: terpstra
—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/2009/08/15/skype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes/&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to Skype call recording with bookmarked, mind-mapped notes - TUAW&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes---tuaw&quot;&gt;Skype call recording with bookmarked, mind-mapped notes - TUAW&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.aol.com/portal?icid=tuaw_head_aol&quot;&gt;AOL.com&lt;/a&gt; |  &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.aol.com/auth/signin.do?returl=http://webmail.aol.com&amp;amp;canurl=http://m.blackvoices.com/portal/default/home.do&quot;&gt;Mail&lt;/a&gt; |  &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.aol.com/search/default?icid=tuaw_head_search&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/aol_logo_header.gif&quot; alt=&quot;AOL&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/AOL_tuawLogo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AOL_tuawLogo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/review/?icid=tuaw_nav_review&quot;&gt;REVIEWS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/howto/?icid=tuaw_nav_howto&quot;&gt;HOW-TO&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/@video/?icid=tuaw_nav_video&quot;&gt;VIDEO&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/deals/?icid=tuaw_nav_deals&quot;&gt;DEALS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/category/features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes&quot;&gt;Skype call recording with bookmarked, mind-mapped notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aug 15th 2009 9:00 AM EDT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BY  &lt;a href=&quot;/bloggers/brett-terpstra/?icid=tuaw__art_author&quot;&gt;Brett Terpstra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/dims-global/dims3/MWAP/resize/240x180/format/jpg/http://www.blogcdn.com/www.tuaw.com/media/2009/08/skype-mindmanager-applescript-250.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been perfecting a very specific efficiency aspect of my workflow: taking notes during Skype calls. I use a Skype-in number as my primary phone number, and – with permission – record client calls for future reference. I can’t tell you how many times this has come in handy. On long calls, though, going back and finding a specific point where something was mentioned can be a time-consuming hassle. What I wanted was the ability to record a Skype call while taking notes, and to then be able to reference my (abbreviated) notes back to the exact point where they were taken in the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve played around extensively with doing this in Pear Note and Transcriva, and both work very well once you get the audio routing right (Soundflower is gold). However, I love taking my notes in a mind map format, and usually create a MindManager map before I start a call. This is especially valuable with long, long calls where keeping things organized and grouped on the fly as the conversation meanders and backtracks can be vital. So I donned my AppleScript hat and started seeing what I could do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using Audio Hijack Pro and Mindjet MindManager 7 Mac in these scripts. I had these readily available and they both have excellent AppleScript dictionaries, thus were conducive to satisfying my requirements. A little hacking could make these work with a variety of other applications. To set this up in Audio Hijack, I used the default Skype session and had my scripts check to see if we were recording, starting it up if we weren’t. From that point, I could add quick bookmarks to my MindManager topics during the conversation. When I read back through my notes, I can instantly play back the associated part of the conversation. Read on to find out how I did it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;record-a-bookmark&quot;&gt;Record a bookmark&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following code will add a callout to the current topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/nextArrow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Next&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://www.tuaw.com/2009/08/15/skype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes/&amp;amp;t=Skype%20call%20recording%20with%20bookmarked,%20mind-mapped%20notes&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/btn_facebook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fshare&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/tweet?articleUrl=http://www.tuaw.com/2009/08/15/skype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes/&amp;amp;title=Skype%20call%20recording%20with%20bookmarked,%20mind-mapped%20notes&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/btn_twitter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filed under&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/category/features/&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/category/productivity/&quot;&gt;Productivity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/category/applescript/&quot;&gt;AppleScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/audio/&quot;&gt;audio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/audio%2Bhijack/&quot;&gt;audio hijack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/audio%2Bhijack%2Bpro/&quot;&gt;audio hijack pro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/AudioHijack/&quot;&gt;AudioHijack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/AudioHijackPro/&quot;&gt;AudioHijackPro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/mindjet%2Bmindmanager/&quot;&gt;mindjet mindmanager&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/mindjet-mindmanager/&quot;&gt;mindjet-mindmanager&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/MindjetMindmanager/&quot;&gt;MindjetMindmanager&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.tuaw.com/tag/notes/&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/bullet_blue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bullet_blue.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/Mac/?icid=tuaw_ql_mac&quot;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/bullet_blue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bullet_blue.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/iPhone/?icid=tuaw_ql_iphone&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/bullet_blue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bullet_blue.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/iPad/?icid=tuaw_ql_ipad&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/bullet_blue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bullet_blue.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/iPod/?icid=tuaw_ql_ipod&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/bullet_blue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bullet_blue.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/Apple%2BTV/?icid=tuaw_ql_appletv&quot;&gt;Apple TV&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/bullet_blue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bullet_blue.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tag/Mac101/?icid=tuaw_ql_mac101&quot;&gt;Mac 101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.aolcdn.com/os/mobileweb/tuaw/prod/images/en/US/AOL_tuawLogo_Footer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AOL_tuawLogo_Footer.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.aol.com/portal/directory?tab=directory&amp;amp;icid=tuaw_ftr_dir&quot;&gt;A-Z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/help?icid=tuaw_ftr_help&quot;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://legal.aol.com/mobiletos&quot;&gt;Privacy/TOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© 2013 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://o.sa.aol.com/b/ss/aolwbtuaw,aolsvc/5/noscript/s2640231028335467200?pageName=Skype%2Bcall%2Brecording%2Bwith%2Bbookmarked%252C%2Bmind-mapped%2Bnotes&amp;amp;ch=us.tuaw_mb&amp;amp;c1=article&amp;amp;c2=features&amp;amp;c10=noscript&amp;amp;c12=http%253A%252F%252Fm.tuaw.com%252F2009%252F08%252F15%252Fskype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes%252F&amp;amp;c13=noscript&amp;amp;c14=noscript&amp;amp;c49=noscript&amp;amp;c54=blogsmith&amp;amp;events=event10&amp;amp;c18=features%7Cproductivity%7Capplescript&amp;amp;c19=audio%7Caudio_hijack%7Caudio_hijack_pro%7CAudioHijack%7CAudioHijackPro%7Cmindjet_mindmanager%7Cmindjet-mindmanager%7CMindjetMindmanager%7Cnotes&amp;amp;c22=brett-terpstra&quot; alt=&quot;s2640231028335467200?pageName=Skype%2bca&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://b.scorecardresearch.com/b2?c1=2&amp;amp;c2=1000009&amp;amp;c4=http%3A%2F%2Fm.tuaw.com%2F2009%2F08%2F15%2Fskype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes%2F&amp;amp;c7=http%3A%2F%2Fm.tuaw.com%2F2009%2F08%2F15%2Fskype-call-recording-with-bookmarked-mind-mapped-notes%2F&amp;amp;c5=us.tuaw_mb&amp;amp;c8=Skype%2Bcall%2Brecording%2Bwith%2Bbookmarked%2C%2Bmind-mapped%2Bnotes&quot; alt=&quot;*&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[Document Created and Edited Using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; Language.]]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/2013/09/08/Podcast%20Mind%20map%20podcast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/2013/09/08/Podcast%20Mind%20map%20podcast/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
