<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes</title>
    <description>My notes in a clean jekyll format.</description>
    <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://Blackoctopus.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Police Notes</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;citizen-police-academy&quot;&gt;Citizen Police Academy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good Morning –&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for some professional Media assistance in marketing JPD’s Citizen Police Academy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dates for the Citizen Police Academy will be Thursday  March 5th though April 30th. We will not have the academy on April 2th due to Easter/Spring break. The time is from 1830-2130 (3  hrs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application is attached and a rough draft of activities.   We want to convey that the deadline is February 10th, as background checks are done on the participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for:
Website post with Link  to application..(ASAP)
G-10
Image/graphics for FB and Email blasts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be great to put it in the water billing and Your City as well.    Please let me know if I can provide anything to facilitate this.  Thanks for all you do for Public Safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beth Purcell
Public Information Officer
Jacksonville Department of Public Safety
Desk:  910-455-1772
Media Line:  910-581-9909&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 05:44:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/jpd/2014/12/16/jpd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/jpd/2014/12/16/jpd/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>holiday notes</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Year’s Holiday Monday collection schedule
December 29, All Day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Year’s Holiday Monday trash, recycle and yard waste collection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Year’s Holiday Tuesday collection schedule
December 30, All Day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Year’s Holiday Tuesday trash, recycle and yard waste collection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Year’s Holiday Thursday collection schedule
December 31, All Day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Year’s Holiday Thursday trash, recycle and yard waste collection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City Offices Closed for Christmas &amp;amp; New Year’s Holidays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City offices will be closed Thursday and Friday, December 25 &amp;amp; 26, 2014 in observance of the Christmas Holiday. Offices will reopen for business Monday, December 29, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City offices will also be closed Thursday, January 1, 2015 for the New Year’s Holiday, Offices will reopen Friday, January 2, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 05:43:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/notes/2014/12/16/HolidaySchedule/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/notes/2014/12/16/HolidaySchedule/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2014 ROLC</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 05:37:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/rolc/2014/12/16/ROLCnotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/rolc/2014/12/16/ROLCnotes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>parks</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;jacksonville-parks&quot;&gt;Jacksonville Parks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=203&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to Jacksonville, NC - Official Website&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pages/N203/riverwalkpark_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Riverwalk Crossing Park&quot; title=&quot;Riverwalk Crossing Park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parks In Jacksonville&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recreation and Parks has a lot to offer! Jacksonville parks are located throughout the city, near neighborhoods, and along our waterways. City parks feature many different amenities including playgrounds, picnic areas, grills, basketball courts, public restrooms, lit shelter areas, and, above all else, nature at its finest. Best of all jacksonville Parks are open to the Citizens and visitors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downtown Parks
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pages/N203/riverwalkpark_2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Riverwalk Crossing Park&quot; title=&quot;Riverwalk Crossing Park&quot; /&gt;In downtown Jacksonville there are five parks located along Wilson Bay and the New River. Visitors will find public access to the water, places to walk, ride a bike, shelters for picnics and outdoor gatherings, trails, greenways, and festivals events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riverwalk Crossing Park &amp;amp; LP Willngham Park located in Jacksonville’s historic district sits on the New River, and is the home to several annual events and festivals including the New River Festival &amp;amp; Palooza, Oktoberfest, Winterfest and National Night Out. There is a stage for live music and extensive landscaping. Walkways lead to the water and a gazebo along the water’s edge for visitor’s to sit and enjoy the view. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pages/N203/sutrgeoncity2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sturgeon City Park&quot; title=&quot;Sturgeon City Park&quot; /&gt;Sturgeon City Park and Wilson Bay Park hug the shore of Wilson Bay. The New River flows by the Wilson Bay and overlooks the Rte 17 Bridge that accesses New River Air Station, Camp Geiger and Camp Lejeune Military Installations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kerr Street Park, 36 Kerr Street
LP Willingham Park, Kerr Street
Riverwalk Crossing Park, 421 Court Street
Sturgeon City Park, 4 Court Street
Wilson Bay Park, 5 West Bayshore Drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacksonville Commons &amp;amp; Richard Ray All American Park
Award winning ball fields, a skate and BMX park, tennis courts, multiple play areas and indoor basketball court are some of the amenities you will find at the Jacksonville Commons located at 100 Recreation Lane, Jacksonville. This area is the home to the annual Running with the Law 5K, a variety of Sports Events and the Jacksonville Jamboree, a spring festival with sports competitions, demonstrations, exhibits, music and loads of family fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacksonville Recreation &amp;amp; Parks Administrative Offices, the City’s Senior Center, and newly floored gymnasium is located at the Jacksonville Commons Recreation Center. Some of the shelters in the Commons outdoor areas, as well as rooms and the gymnasium at the Commons Recreation Center are available for rental. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacksonville Commons, 100 Recreation Lane
Richard Ray All American Park, 1200 Commons Drive North&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pages/N203/northeastcreek_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Northeast Creek Park, Frisbee Golf&quot; title=&quot;Northeast Creek Park, Frisbee Golf&quot; /&gt;Northeast Creek Park and Jacksonville Landing
Need to get on the water? Get your boat, kayak, canoe or paddle board and head for the Jacksonville Landing in downtown Jacksonville or Northeast Creek Park on Corbin Road to access the areas many waterways. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northeast Creek Park has beautifully maintained ball fields, a regulation Frisbee Golf Course and a boat launch that can serve two boats at a time. This park is home to the annual Frisbee Golf Competition that takes place in the fall and attracts players from near and far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jacksonville Landing is a new addition to the City and will be available for public use in 2014. This public launch accesses the New River at Marine Blvd next to the newly renovated Buddy Phillips Bridge. A green space and walkway is planned along the water, as well as a Welcome Center for visitors. A  kayak launch and launch area that services up to three boats at a time is included at this location.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northeast Creek Park, 910 Corbin Road
Jacksonville Landing, Marine Blvd at Buddy Phillips Bridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pages/N203/phillipspark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Phillips Park, shelter&quot; title=&quot;Phillips Park, shelter&quot; /&gt;Neighborhood Parks
Jacksonville has several neighborhood parks that have varying facilities and views. These parks, although smaller in size compared to others, have a charm of their own and serve the City’s Citizens in unique ways. Visitors will find play areas for their children, shelters for public use, sports fields, well maintained landscaping, water views and quiet places to walk and relax. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branchwood Park, 305 Audubon Drive
Brook Valley Park, 350 Estate Drive
Georgetown Park, 250 Georgetown Road
Phillips Park, 150 Philips Road
Rev EW Wooten Park, 203 A Cole Drive
Sherwood Forrest, 212 A Nottingham Way
Woodlands Park, 300 Morgan Road&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacksonville Recreation Centers
Jacksonville Commons, Jacks Amyette, Kerr Street and Northwoods Recreation Centers are the place to be for many family fun oriented activities both indoors and outdoors. After School programs, Summer Camps, Seasonal events, programs, classes and more are available to the public. Tap into the Jacksonville Recreation web pages for the latest activities available to you and your family. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?nid=197&quot;&gt;Recreation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacksonville Commons Recreation Center, 100 Recreation Lane
Jack Amyette Recreation Center, 1825 South Drive
Kerr Street Recreation Center, 36 Kerr Street
Northwoods Recreation Center, 621 Henderson Drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=209&quot;&gt;Facility &amp;amp; Park Rentals&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=624&quot;&gt;Park Rule &amp;amp; Regulations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopt - A - Park or Trail
The City of Jacksonville Adopt-A-Park or Trail is a great way to give back locally and make a difference in your community. Help keep Jacksonville Clean &amp;amp; Green.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?nid=570&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 09:37:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/coj/2014/12/08/parks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/coj/2014/12/08/parks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ROLC Christmas</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-king-is-born-christmas-concert&quot;&gt;A King Is Born” Christmas Concert&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-meeting-12-20&quot;&gt;Special Meeting 12-20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--BREAK--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;AUDIO&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Video&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Snapshot&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;who&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;media&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Welcome&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PRC&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Welcome-Pastor Chris&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Appx 6:05&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;club57&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12 Christmas Prayers-Band playing softly in the background&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;who&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;media&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2:04&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A Christmas Narrative&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;3 videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Narrative video &lt;strong&gt;presentation&lt;/strong&gt;
### 2:08Video &lt;strong&gt;spoken word&lt;/strong&gt; HD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRC 15mins presentation meaning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lights down then use light at to risers &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cue kids to risers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Song&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;joy to the world video &lt;em&gt;mute audio&lt;/em&gt;
*Sync eyeball manual
Trio 
# Emanuel :build graphic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 12:58:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/christmas/2014/11/25/Rolc-1220TA/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/christmas/2014/11/25/Rolc-1220TA/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>website 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-design-a-mockup/&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch: Design a Mockup&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-design-a-mockup&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch: Design a Mockup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/series/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch/&quot; title=&quot;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/building-a-responsive-website-introduction/&quot; title=&quot;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch: Introduction&quot;&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt; of this brand new series, I have introduced the main objectives of the series and given a short but complete introduction on the critical components of media queries and responsive breakpoints. Now, it’s time to begin doing some practical work. As I have mentioned before, I’ll start with the planning and creation of a mockup for each of the three main device types on which our responsive website will be designed, tested, and displayed: PC desktops, tablets, and mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-start&quot;&gt;3…2…1… Let’s Start!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before continuing, I want to give you a little advice: remember that the more mockups you do, the more arduous and confusing your job will become. Responsive mockups are not the same as static mockups; you don’t really know where your content will be placed, because it depends on the screen size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, as we’ve seen in the previous series, designing mockups for every screen size is nearly impossible, because there are potentially hundreds of screens, layouts, and orientations that you have to accommodate. This is why I suggest that you select your target screens/layouts and build the project mockups only for your top three main devices’ categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For obvious reasons, I won’t show you how to design and build the entire website, but I’ll focus on the homepage, although I’m sure that once you have understood the logic and basis of responsive web design, you’ll be able to proceed with building the entire portal and everything will fall into place. I should reiterate that creating mockups doesn’t usually require that you lay out every single view to perfection, and that they are effective as soon as they’re enough of an abstraction of the final product (website or app) that they give you sufficient information to begin building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have chosen to build my project mockup using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/build-a-project-mockup-using-balsamiq/&quot; title=&quot;Build a project mockup using Balsamiq&quot;&gt;Balsamiq Mockups&lt;/a&gt;. As I have explained in detail in the linked article, Balsamiq Mockups is a tool that helps developers to create wireframes and communicate with clients and coworkers with visual representations of their design plans. Balsamiq is offline desktop software, and you can work with it using the operating system of your choice, since it runs on Mac, Windows, and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start planning the mockup of our website working on the PC desktop version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, let me introduce the kind of website we’re going to desogm and all of the elements that we’ll find within it. In fact, when building a web app or website, it’s a good practice to identify your content ahead of time and designate respective content areas within the website template. For our purposes, we’ll build a website with main content topics like graphics, web design and mobile development, a place where the design-addicted can read articles about their favourite fields, discuss, learn new techniques, and stay informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see how can we proceed using the elements of Balsamiq Mockups and focus on one target layout first. We have to work on the placement of blocks on the layouts, and as a first step, I place the browser window shape to represent the profile of any browser page and set its size using slight adjustments with the mouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the style of the main page, the first thing to determine is which elements we want to show on our brand new homepage. Generally, we might find a header, a newsletter bar, a menu-list, some sidebars (based on the extra-content you want to enter), a text box for the most important information, an image, or some links, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to its simple, intuitive drag-and-drop system, we can easily add everything we want with a few clicks. For the first components of our page, we have to open the category called “Big.” Here, we’ll find the following elements elements: title/headline, the text area, and the image box. So, drag and drop each of these into your mockup.  Then, open the category “Common” to find rectangles, text areas, text input boxes, image and icons’ indicators, and link pointers. Let’s place the two sidebars to the left of the author information box (where it could be nice adding a photo) under the main content box, which occupies the full window width.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, our design concept should look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dab1nmslvvntp.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/pc-desktop-mockup1.png&quot; alt=&quot;pc-desktop-mockup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve dragged and dropped the elements, you’ll see that each element has extensive editing options. When you click on the title/headline or within the text box, you’ll see a typical text editor, where you’ll be able to specify the characteristics or content. You can modify texts selecting size, text alignment, format, and color. You can also set the background color, set the border color, add a scrollbar, and play with opacity and focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For images, we can show or hide a border, crop the image, and hyperlink the chosen image to lead to a new URL or screen. Since this is a mockup project intended mainly to keep in mind all the page elements and their arrangement, is not necessary in my opinion to make ultra-precise stylistic changes. What is important is to have a sort of “skeleton,” or a point of departure to fix attention on what is necessary to build into the structure with the help of the HTML code and the CSS3 styling rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’re done with this first passage, let’s continue planning our tablet version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dab1nmslvvntp.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tablet-mockup.png&quot; alt=&quot;tablet-mockup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the image above, all the elements used in this second mockup are the same; the only thing that has changed is their arrangement. In the top part of the page, almost everything has the same style: the banner and the newsletter bar occupy all the window width on the PC desktop as well as the tablet version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; changed is the alignment of the menu-list items. In order to make the reading of menu items clear and easy even on a screen with a reduced size, I have planned to increase the space between all the present items. Additionally, the bottom part of the mockup introduces some slight changes: the sidebars that were placed on the left side of the author box have been moved under this and positioned next to each other in order to give them a larger width. Look below for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dab1nmslvvntp.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/smartphone-mockup-1024x521.png&quot; alt=&quot;smartphone-mockup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our last step in the mockup process, let’s tackle the smartphone version.  I have placed the iPhone shape (as said before, it’s the only one available to represent the profile of all modern smartphones) and duplicated it twice to allow you to view what the user would see by scrolling through the site from the top to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, for the top part of the portal, the arrangement of the newsletter elements has changed, andthe menu-item list is also different compared to the PC desktop and tablet mockups. The input box and the submit button are presented vertically in order to make the process of writing and sending data faster and simpler. As for the menu, the best solution to adopt in this case (since the menu is composed of only five items) is to create a drop-down menu that the user can easily touch to load the page he desires to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the other components of the page are set to their max width to make the content intuitive and accessible. Even if at this stage you cannot see it, for the text view, you can think about a simple trick to make your users satisfied. Remember that, if your content is too long, they would have to scroll down the page many times to reach the end, and this could easily cause disorientation and boredom. So you could solve this “too much content” problem by placing a “Read more” link that takes the user directly to the information he demands and makes the homepage more streamlined, easier to load, and pleasant to visit, even on a narrow smartphone screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ve seen how to build a project mockup thinking responsively and—consequently—how a responsive design can adapt to three target layouts: Default (PC desktop), Portrait Tablet, and Smartphone. We’ve seen how to arrange the elements of a typical website in the three main devices’ categories by creating a template that represents the common content elements. In the third part of this series, we’ll start to write the HTML code and work on the structure of the homepage and set the first CSS styling rules to build an initial design.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 09:10:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/web/2014/11/21/site3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/web/2014/11/21/site3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Memorial Gardens</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?nid=648&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to Jacksonville, NC - Official Website&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;jacksonville-nc---official-website&quot;&gt;Jacksonville, NC - Official Website&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens in Jacksonville is home to the Beirut Memorial, Onslow Vietnam Veteran’s Memorial and the 9/11 Memorial. Acreage within the gardens is reserved for future memorials, an amphitheater and the Museum of the Marine. Lejeune Memorial Gardens is located on Montford Point Road near the Freedom Fountain, downtown Jacksonville and the entrance to Camp Geiger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free parking is available on Montford Point Road at the entrance to Lejeune Memorial Gardens. Informational Placards are located at the site. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?nid=224&quot;&gt;Jacksonville Transit&lt;/a&gt; has a stop located within walking distance to Lejeune Memorial Gardens.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jacksonvilleonline.org&quot;&gt;Jacksonville-Onslow Chamber of Commerce&lt;/a&gt; website includes a listing of places to stay in Jacksonville during your visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing Memorials at Lejeune Memorial Gardens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/2014-10-Beirut_Mem_Observance-IMG_1961.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beirut Memorial, Jacksonville NC&quot; /&gt;Beirut Memorial
The Beirut Memorial was a gift from the citizens of Onslow County to honor the men that lived among us and gave so much. A solemn tribute to 273 Marines who gave their lives in Lebanon and Grenada on October 23, 1983. The names of each man are engraved in granite along with the words “They Came In Peace.” An annual Observance remembers those who lost theirs lives during the Beirut Peace Mission in 1983. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=585&quot;&gt;visit web page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/2014-VVMemorial9w.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Onslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial&quot; /&gt;O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial
The Onslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial is dedicated to all men and women who served during the Vietnam War, and stands as recognition for the nearly ten million Veterans of the five branches of the Armed Forces who served on active duty during the Vietnam era, nearly three million of whom served in the Vietnam theater. The Onslow Vietnam Veterans Memorial is one of the largest Vietnam Veterans Memorials in the nation and one of only a few that lists all the names of the fallen. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=599&quot;&gt;visit web page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/2014-09-11-Patriot-Day-9-11-Althouse-A3608.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2014-09-11-Patriot-Day-9-11-Althouse-A3608.jpg&quot; /&gt;9/11 Memorial Beam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 9/11 Memorial includes a beam from the Twin Towers, presented to the first troops to those who invaded Iraq from the police and firefighters of New York.  The Beam is located by the Beirut Memorial and Entry Wall to the Vietnam Veterans Memorial at Lejeune Memorial Gardens in Jacksonville. An annual Patriot Day Observance remembers those who lost theirs lives during the terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001 and those who continue to fight the war on terror. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=553&quot;&gt;visit web page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/MasterPlan1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beirut Memorial Master plan&quot; /&gt;Plans for the Future at Lejeune Memorial Gardens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens Master Plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plans for the future include the Corpsman Memorial, Montford Point Memorial, Museum of the Marine and the Lejeune Greenway &amp;amp; Trail. The site also includes space for additional memorials. Click on the Map for a larger view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional Information please contact the City Manager’s Office at City Hall, 815 New Bridge Street, 910 938-5200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/corpsmenmemorialmodel-shapeimage_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Corpsmen Memorial Model&quot; /&gt;Corpsmen Memorial&lt;/strong&gt; - In February 2008, the Corpsmen Memorial Foundation was established with the goal of creating a monument in honor of Navy corpsmen who fought alongside their Marine brethren. The Corpsmen Memorial will be a life-sized replica of the clay sculpture currently housed in Naval Hospital Camp Lejeune, which portrays a Vietnam-era corpsman lying on top of a wounded Marine, whose right leg is in a makeshift splint, shielding him from impending danger. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funds have been accumulated over the past two and a half years, totaling nearly $30,000. The memorial is scheduled to be completed and placed in the Lejeune Memorial Gardens near Camp Johnson within the next two years, if the necessary funds are met. &lt;a href=&quot;http://nccorpsmenmemorial.net/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/montfordpointmemorial02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Montford Point Marine Memorial&quot; /&gt;Montford Point Marine Memorial&lt;/strong&gt; - President Barack Obama once said, “Despite being denied many basic rights, the Montford Point Marines committed to serve our country with selfless patriotism… Embodying the Marine Corps motto of Semper Fidelis, Always Faithful, these heroes paved the way for future generations of warriors, regardless of background, to serve in the finest military the world has ever known.” Funding is underway and a memorial to honor the Montford Point Marines is planned for Lejeune Memorial Gardens. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mpmamemorial.com/&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/images/pages/N648/rendering-museum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Museum of the Marine rendering&quot; /&gt;Museum of the Marine&lt;/strong&gt; - The Museum of the Marine is designed to pay tribute to the exceptional men and women, the Carolina Marines, whose training prepared them for service and leadership in the defense of our country and freedom worldwide. Within the walls of this 40,000-square-foot facility, we will tell the stories of the Carolina Marines, their units, bases and stations and epic battles, and of the Carolina communities that have supported them. Funding is underway for the museum that will be a wonderful addition to the Lejeune Memorial Gardens. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.museumofthemarine.org/&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lejeune Memorial Gardens Greenway &amp;amp; Trail&lt;/strong&gt; - Following the transition of former railroad tracks into trails to the base, in 2007 the City won funds to begin work on a missing connector from downtown Jacksonville to the current pathway into Camp Lejeune at the point of the iconic pedestrian bridge over Lejeune Boulevard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Jacksonville Greenway Trail is installed it will be with reverence to all of the memorials within Lejeune Memorial Gardens.  The path is connection. It will connect the Civilian community of Jacksonville with the Military community of Camp Lejeune. It will connect the revitalized Downtown area with pedestrians both on foot and on bikes.  Most importantly the Jacksonville Greenway Trail is a connection to our past.  It will connect visitors to Lejeune Memorial Gardens and to those who have made the ultimate sacrifice in service to our Country.  It will connect future generations to the adversities overcome by the first black Marines at the Montford Point Marines Memorial and to the history of all who have served at the Museum of the Marine. The Jacksonville Greenway Trail will allow greater access for everyone to a site that preserves and honors the legacies of America’s finest. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacksonvillenc.gov/index.aspx?NID=644&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 08:54:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/jacksonville/2014/11/21/gardens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/jacksonville/2014/11/21/gardens/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X feedly</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x-feedly&quot;&gt;Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X feedly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blackoctopus.net/2014/10/creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x-feedly/&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X feedly&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alex4d.com/notes/item/creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x&quot;&gt;Creating Apple Store iOS App Previews using Final Cut Pro X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
// &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alex4d.com/notes/item/creating-apple-store-ios-app-previews-using-final-cut-pro-x&quot;&gt;Final Cut Pro X and Post Production Blog – Alex4D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those iOS developers who want to provide more information to potential purchasers in the iOS app store, Apple suggest using video-based ‘app previews.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple have provided &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/app-previews/&quot;&gt; resources for developers&lt;/a&gt; who want to create app previews using iMovie 10.0.6 and Final Cut Pro X 10.1.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New in OS X Yosemite is the ability to record what happens on an iOS 8 device attached to your Mac. Here’s an excerpt from Apple’s instructions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;capture-screen-recordings-with-quicktime-player&quot;&gt;Capture Screen Recordings with QuickTime Player&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect your iOS device to your Mac using a Lightning cable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open QuickTime Player.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose File &amp;gt; New Movie Recording.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the window that appears, select your iOS device as the Camera and Microphone input source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1.wp.com/alex4d.com/images/alex4dNotes/2014/1024_AppPrev/AP-choose-iPhone-source.jpg?resize=371%2C181&quot; alt=&quot;AP-choose-iPhone-source&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you use the Record button, perform the actions on your iOS device that demonstrate the features of the app, you save the recording on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-cut-pro-x-app-preview-settings&quot;&gt;Final Cut Pro X app preview settings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/app-previews/final-cut-pro/Creating-App-Previews-with-Final-Cut-Pro-X.pdf&quot;&gt; PDF of instructions&lt;/a&gt; for those new to Final Cut Pro on how to create new projects and which custom size to use for each app preview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 5s, iPhone 5c, iPod touch 5th generation: 640 x 1136 for portrait, 1136 x 640 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 6: 750 x 1334 for portrait, 1334 x 750 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad Air, iPad 4th generation, iPad mini with Retina display: 900 x 1200 for portrait, 1200 x 900 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 6 Plus 1080 x 1920 for portrait, 1920 x 1080 for landscape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;App previews must be set to a frame rate of 30p.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;free-titles&quot;&gt;11 free titles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as the short PDF guide Apple also provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/app-previews/final-cut-pro/downloads/app-preview-titles.zip&quot;&gt; a set of free title plugins&lt;/a&gt; (12.2MB ZIP) to provide useful information in overlays on top of screen recordings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i2.wp.com/alex4d.com/images/alex4dNotes/2014/1024_AppPrev/APtitles-in-browser.jpg?resize=229%2C628&quot; alt=&quot;APtitles-in-browser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ZIP includes installation instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-market&quot;&gt;A new market?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For writer/editors, creating iOS app previews might become a marketable skill: “Sales for this app were low, but after using the services of &lt;em&gt;AppPreview4D&lt;/em&gt;, everything changed!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedly.com&quot;&gt;my feedly reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 09:53:45 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/ios/2014/10/29/iOS-App-Previews/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/ios/2014/10/29/iOS-App-Previews/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>icecast tutorial</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;icecast-and-darkice&quot;&gt;icecast and darkice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dzello.com/blog/2012/11/21/live-stream-audio-from-osx-mountain-lion-with-icecast-and-darkice&quot;&gt;ICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any team can benefit from a widely-accessible streaming music server. Sharing the same music increases team flow and builds &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/talk/play&quot;&gt;culture&lt;/a&gt;. And funny things happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share both music and announcements, &lt;a href=&quot;http://party.io&quot;&gt;party.io&lt;/a&gt; uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/play/play&quot;&gt;Play&lt;/a&gt; from Github. Play is an ‘employee-powered iTunes-based client-driven distributed music server for your office’. Our company DJ (a big-hearted, chrome-plated &lt;a href=&quot;http://hubot.github.com/&quot;&gt;hubot&lt;/a&gt;) manages Play and occasionally accepts submissions from the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play syncs the company song queue, but a streaming audio server is still needed to stream what’s playing. There are products that do this; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rogueamoeba.com/nicecast/&quot;&gt;Nicecast&lt;/a&gt; is one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also build an open-source frankenstack for free. It’s &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; four pieces: &lt;a href=&quot;http://cycling74.com/products/soundflower/&quot;&gt;Soundflower&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jackaudio.org/&quot;&gt;Jack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://darkice.org/&quot;&gt;Darkice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icecast.org/&quot;&gt;Icecast&lt;/a&gt;. This post explains how to put these pieces together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s a little more work, the outcome is the ability to stream &lt;strong&gt;system audio&lt;/strong&gt; anywhere. This makes more scenarios possible and it requires less maintenance - there’s no requirement to add media files in advance or to configure any applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can hear it, you can stream it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;before-starting&quot;&gt;Before starting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need the latest compiler installed, whether via XCode or the OSX Mountain Lion Command Line Tools installation at &lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.apple.com/&quot;&gt;http://connect.apple.com/&lt;/a&gt; (recommended if you don’t need all of XCode). You’ll need to be somewhat comfortable with working on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Beginning..._Was_the_Command_Line&quot;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure you have &lt;a href=&quot;http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; installed. And make sure to run &lt;code&gt;brew update&lt;/code&gt; before beginning, and &lt;code&gt;brew doctor&lt;/code&gt; if anything goes wrong along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-soundflower&quot;&gt;Installation: Soundflower&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soundflower is an inter-application audio routing utility. Soundflower creates additional audio devices that bind to applications to send and receive audio. Soundflower also comes with a program called Soundflowerbed. It lets you listen to audio locally even while broadcasting, like a splitter. Here’s what the Soundflowerbed menu bar app looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/soundflowerbed.png&quot; alt=&quot;Soundflowerbed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cycling74.com/soundflower-landing-page/&quot;&gt;Download Soundflower here&lt;/a&gt; and install it. Homebrew doesn’t have a Soundflower formula AFAIK, but thankfully there’s nothing tricky to this installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve restarted we’ll install the next component, Jack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-jack&quot;&gt;Installation: Jack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack is a professional quality audio tool that can also route audio between applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack had problems initially with Mac OSX 10.7.3+, but a beta version seems to have worked the bugs out. Neither the Homebrew formula nor the latest download on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jackosx.com/download.html&quot;&gt;jackosx.com&lt;/a&gt; have the new code, but you can find it on the Jack-OSX Yahoo group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a link to the 0.90b8 beta package on &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/jackosx/message/3945&quot;&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt;. Download and install it, restarting when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, start the Soundflowerbed app (in /Applications/Soundflower) and choose the ‘Audio Setup’ option from the menu bar icon it installs. This will launch the System Audio Midi Setup menu. Set both input and output to Soundflower (2ch), like in the image below. Also make sure the volume is up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/audiomidisetup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Audio Midi Setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we can start Jack as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;➜  ~  jackdmp -d coreaudio
jackdmp 1.9.9
Copyright 2001-2005 Paul Davis and others.
Copyright 2004-2012 Grame.
jackdmp comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY
This is free software, and you are welcome to redistribute it
under certain conditions; see the file COPYING for details
JACK server starting in realtime mode with priority 10
Input channel = 0 ==&amp;gt; JACK input port = 0
Input channel = 1 ==&amp;gt; JACK input port = 1
JACK output port = 0 ==&amp;gt; output channel = 0
JACK output port = 1 ==&amp;gt; output channel = 1
CoreAudio driver is running...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack will now be running and can pass audio from Soundflower into our next component, Darkice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-darkice&quot;&gt;Installation: Darkice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darkice is a live audio streamer. In our setup, it’s responsible for encoding the audio from Jack (into MP3, Ogg Vorbis, et. al.) and sending it to Icecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll install Darkice with Homebrew but this gets a little weird. Darkice has a dependency on Jack, but Homebrew doesn’t know we’ve already installed Jack through another means. So we have to install a ‘dummy’, unlinked Jack so Homebrew thinks the Jack dependency is satisfied but Darkice builds against the downloaded Jack and not the Homebrew Jack (this is essential).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


brew install darkice --use-llvm   #ignore the linking warnings for Jack - Darkice must complete without Jack linked!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this process Jack will fail to link and issue a warning but the script will still continue. This is good, because Darkice will then build against the downloaded Jack. If things blow up which installing dependencies, install without the llvm flag and then retry this again. The goal is just to get the Jack-failed-link and the Darkice build in the same step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-icecast&quot;&gt;Installation: Icecast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Icecast is the web-serving layer of our stack, accepting incoming client connections and then broadacsting out the stream it receives from Darkice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Icecast with Homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


brew install icecast
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;running-icecast-and-darkice&quot;&gt;Running Icecast and Darkice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a config file for Icecast: download this sample &lt;a href=&quot;/images/icecast.xml&quot;&gt;icecast.xml&lt;/a&gt; I’ve put together for this tutorial into &lt;code&gt;~/.icecast.xml&lt;/code&gt;. Now we can start Icecast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


icecast -c ~/.icecast.xml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need a config file for darkice: download this sample &lt;a href=&quot;/images/darkice.cfg&quot;&gt;darkice.cfg&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;code&gt;~/.darkice.cfg&lt;/code&gt;. Once you have it saved, let’s start Darkice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


darkice -c ~/.darkice.cfg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can now check our status by logging into Icecast’s administration UI. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8000/admin/&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8000/admin/&lt;/a&gt; and enter the admin-user and admin-password from the icecast.xml config file. You should arrive at the admin page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/icecast.png&quot; alt=&quot;Icecast Admin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you should see an area below that shows the active mount point, created by Darkice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dubspin.png&quot; alt=&quot;Icecast with Darkice mount&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;testing-with-a-client&quot;&gt;Testing with a client&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, head over to another computer on your network, or your smartphone, and head for to the streaming address we’ve set up. The URL should look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1


http://computer.local:8000/spin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Substitute ‘computer.local’ for the hostname or IP address of your computer. ‘spin’ is the name of the mountpoint we specified in darkice.cfg (and 8000 the port).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paste the URL into Safari on Mac or iOS and you should get playback in iTunes / iOS Quicktime respectively:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/itunes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Streaming from iTunes&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/iphone.png&quot; alt=&quot;Streaming on iPhone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you, your team, or the whole Internet can listen to your music, broadcasts, and the output of the command &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/library/mac/#documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man1/say.1.html&quot;&gt;say&lt;/a&gt;! Flex the golden pipes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;configure-your-router&quot;&gt;Configure your router&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t be able to access your streaming server from outside your home network unless your open the appropriate ports on your router. In this example, you’d open port 8000. Your router’s instruction manual can you tell you how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bonus-gist&quot;&gt;Bonus Gist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get it all to work, you might want to run these programs in the background and on startup. I wrote up a few basic plist files to be used with launchd that do just that. You can find them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/4126599&quot;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creators of all of these fine tools. This article: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dudek.org/blog/140&quot;&gt;Broadcasting music to multiple speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 01:47:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/notes/2014/10/29/live-stream-audio-from-osx-mountain-lion-with-icecast-and-darkice/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/notes/2014/10/29/live-stream-audio-from-osx-mountain-lion-with-icecast-and-darkice/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Website part 1 of 6</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch-introduction&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch: Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/building-a-responsive-website-introduction/&quot;&gt;http://www.sitepoint.com/building-a-responsive-website-introduction/&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/42bd81912daf039b7faa53dbf9efcb25?s=96&amp;amp;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&amp;amp;r=G&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt;Annarita Tranfici&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published March 25, 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share?text=Build+a+Responsive%2C+Mobile-Friendly+Website+From+Scratch%3A+Introduction&amp;amp;via=sitepointdotcom&quot;&gt; __ Tweet &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://confirmsubscription.com/h/y/1FD5B523FA48AA2B&quot;&gt; Subscribe &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-entry-is-part-1-of-6-in-the-series-build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratchhttpwwwsitepointcomseriesbuild-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch&quot;&gt;This entry is part 1 of 6 in the series &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/series/build-a-responsive-mobile-friendly-website-from-scratch/&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive, Mobile-Friendly Website From Scratch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last series (“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/series/understanding-responsive-web-design/&quot;&gt;Understanding Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt;”), I defined the basic features of this new and important responsive approach to mobile-friendly, device-agnostic design. Now, let’s set the stage for a more concrete work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen that there are many aspects to take into consideration throughout the responsive design process: screen size, operating platform, user behavior, and so on. We have explored the various measurement options for fonts in a website, and we’ve covered the best way to approach &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/understanding-responsive-web-design-how-to-manage-fonts/&quot;&gt;typography&lt;/a&gt; in terms of responsive web design. We’ve explored the characteristics of four different &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/responsive-web-design-fluid-layouts/&quot;&gt;layout types&lt;/a&gt; and their respective fields of implementation. We’ve covered some common problems that a web designer may encounter when managing responsive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/understanding-responsive-web-design-how-to-manage-images/&quot;&gt;images&lt;/a&gt; (and pointed out potential solutions). Finally, we’ve explored the problem of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/understanding-responsive-web-design-cross-browser-compatibility/&quot;&gt;cross-browser compatibility&lt;/a&gt; and proposed different ways to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to demonstrate some &lt;strong&gt;real-world technical applications&lt;/strong&gt; of the responsive web design and build a real responsive website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objectives&quot;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with defining the objectives of this new series, and highlight what you’ll learn. Thanks to this tutorial…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll learn how to create a responsive design mockup, taking into account the main features of a website, the users’ needs, and the way to effectively combine responsive graphics and web design. The mockup of the website won’t be unique to one platform, and it’ll provide an example of the possible structure of a portal from several standpoints—imagining the view on three different devices: smartphones, tablets, and desktop PCs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll learn how to take full advantage of modern web technologies, namely HTML5 and CSS3, applying them step-by-step to each component of your web content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll see how to implement some rules related to responsive web design, by applying what we have analyzed conceptually in prior articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;media-queries&quot;&gt;Media Queries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the foundations or responsive design is &lt;strong&gt;media queries&lt;/strong&gt;, which ultimately make the site accessible and usable by the largest number of users, including those who do not use recent versions of popular browsers such as Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, and Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by getting our hands dirty with media queries; they represent one the most important tools that a web designer has to make their website responsive and mobile-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media queries are composed of &lt;strong&gt;two main parts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@ media screen&lt;/strong&gt; — The first part of a media query is the type of support. You might recognize this syntax from writing your own CSS styles, especially if you used this method before when designing printing options for your website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;min-width: 500px&lt;/strong&gt;) — The second part is the query itself. It includes the function to be evaluated (in this case, the minimum width of the browser window) and the corresponding value to test that the rule has been applied (in this case, a value of 500px).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about responsive web design, there is a tendency to focus exclusively on the width property, but there quite a few other attributes to consider when designing for a variety of screen sizes. There are many more valid properties associated with media queries. They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;width / height&lt;/strong&gt; — With these properties, you can set the width and height of the display area including any scroll bar. You can use the prefixes min and max.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;device-width/height&lt;/strong&gt; — These properties set the width and the height of the rendering surface, that is, the width and height of the entire screen of the device and not simply of the display area of the document. Even in this case, you can still use the min and max prefixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;orientation&lt;/strong&gt; — it sets a vertical or horizontal orientation. By specifying particular rules in the CSS stylesheet, you will be able to define how the various elements of a web page will be displayed on the device, in this case, depending on the orientation of the device we use. We can then specify the type of orientation; landscape and portrait that allow us to change the layout of your design according to the current orientation of the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aspect-ratio&lt;/strong&gt; — This is a property that sets the ratio between the width and height of the display of a document. Even in this case, you can &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; use the min and max prefixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;device-aspect-ratio&lt;/strong&gt; — This attribute monitors the ratio between the width and height of the device. Prefixes min and max are allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; — This applies certain CSS styles for all color devices. Prefixes min and max are allowed, but very few black and white devices (besides inexpensive Kindles) remain as popular browsing options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color-index&lt;/strong&gt; — This describes the number of colors in the palette supported by a device. It can have min and max prefixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;monochrome&lt;/strong&gt; — This property indicates the number of bits per pixel of a monochrome device (grayscale).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;resolution —&lt;/strong&gt; Resolution sets the resolution (i.e. the density of pixels) of the output device. The values ​​of the resolution can be expressed in DPI (dots per inch) or in DPCM (dots per centimeter).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scan&lt;/strong&gt; — a valid property for television screens that indicates the type of scan, interlaced or progressive. The values ​​can be precisely progressive or interlaced.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grid&lt;/strong&gt; — Grid indicates whether the device is a bitmap type or a “grid” equivalent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this short overview of the main (and often underutilized) properties of media queries, let’s proceed by pointing out what are the best responsive &lt;strong&gt;breakpoints&lt;/strong&gt; and how to determine them for a given project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakpoints in terms of responsive web design are browser widths that have a media query declaration to change the layout once the browser is within a declared width range. More specifically, a breakpoint is a point on a line that starts from 0, where there is a change (via CSS) within the layout of the page. Breakpoints are defined with numeric values ​​and units of measurement based on the media queries entered into your CSS stylesheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, every responsive website has a minimum of two breakpoints — one for tablets and one for mobile devices. Each breakpoint corresponds to a media query. In the media query below, I wrote CSS that only takes effect when the minimum width of the browser window (min-width) is equal to a specific value (that can be 320px, 480px, 768px, etc..).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of one of these standard breakpoints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@media only screen and (min-width : 320px) {

/* Styles */

}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, &lt;strong&gt;how many breakpoints does a web designer need to create?&lt;/strong&gt; This depends on the characteristics of the website, on its layout, and on the techniques that you decided to implement in order to turn your design plans into something truly interactive and responsive In essence, we could answer the previous question in this way: You need a breakpoint for every device that you deliberately choose to support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;breakpoints-according-to-the-devices&quot;&gt;Breakpoints According to the Devices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the prevailing practice tends to set breakpoints based on the size of the screen (or browser window) of the following popular device types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smartphone (with portrait or landscape orientation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tablet (with portrait or landscape orientation as well)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Netbook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop PC monitor with high or very high resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translating this scheme into pixels, you can see how for smartphone and tablet categories, the “standard” sizes adopted mainly correspond to the screen dimensions of the iPhone and iPad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;320px — iPhone in portrait orientation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;480px — iPhone in landscape orientation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;768px — iPad in portrait orientation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1024px — iPad in landscape orientation (as well as netbooks, since these devices typically have a horizontal resolution of 1024px).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone might argue that not all smartphones and tablets are iPhones or iPads, and they’d be unquestionably correct. But, in this case the screen size of the Apple device is used more as a reference point for a greater category of devices. Moreover, creating a breakpoint for each and every device would be totally absurd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good practice could be defining a set of main breakpoints possibly combined with some secondary breakpoints in order to fit the document to specific devices. You could also think about creating a custom breakpoint; this is very straightforward but requires a familiarity with media queries, so I suggest practicing initially with basic media queries and common breakpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s extremely important to test your dynamic layouts, including the breakpoints themselves, and the CSS that executes under certain screen size conditions. If you do not have both of those aspects of your responsive design in good order, you’ll end up with glaring layout and functionality problems that make your website less responsive than if you hadn’t attempted any mobile-friendly accommodations. Test your designs thoroughly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have introduced the main objectives of the series, and above all, I have given a short but complete introduction on the critical components of media queries and responsive breakpoints. In the next article, I’ll start with the planning and the creation of a mockup for each of the three main device types on which our website will be designed, tested, and displayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to learn more about Responsive Web Design? Check out SitePoint’s new book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/books/responsive1/&quot;&gt;Jump Start Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/42bd81912daf039b7faa53dbf9efcb25?s=96&amp;amp;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&amp;amp;r=G&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/atranfici/&quot;&gt;Annarita Tranfici&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a Bachelor’s degree in European languages, cultures, and literature from the University of Naples. I’m passionate about graphics and web design, and for several years I’ve been working on projects and designs for many companies. I’m a writer for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ug.audero.it/&quot;&gt;Audero User Group&lt;/a&gt;; my specialties are HTML, CSS, Web Design, and Adobe Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-might-also-like&quot;&gt;You might also like:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/author/jechessa/&quot;&gt;Joyce Echessa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feb 10, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2sis3lil8ndrq.cloudfront.net/books/jshtml-basics1_medium_3d.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab a free copy of one our latest ebooks! Packed with hints and tips on HTML5’s most powerful new features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 12:31:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://Blackoctopus.github.io/3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Blackoctopus.github.io/3/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
